昔々　ある所に
Once upon a time.
In a certain land.
There lived a young girl
とてもおしゃべりで　とても夢見がちな女の子がおりました
who was very talkative,
and given to flights of fancy.
その女の子は　お山の上にある　お城に憧れていました
And this young girl...
was enamored with the castle
on top of the mountain.
Empty / Full
Beautiful.
ステキ
女の子な夢見ます
The young girl dreams.
NOTICE Rest Rate: 5,000
yen Stay Rate: 7,000 yen
「いつか私もステキな王子様とお城の舞踏会へ…」
"Someday, I, too,
will head to the ball at the castle
with a charming prince!"
Daddy?
パ…パパ！？
ママ！ママ！
Mommy! Mommy!
Thank you for your hard work
あら　おかえり
Oh, welcome home.
ただいま
I'm home! Mommy!
Guess what, guess what!
ママ　あのね　あのね
- Just now, I found out about a huge secret!
- Here you go, some fried egg!
さっきね　順ね　すごい秘密を　知っちゃった
玉子焼きでお口　ポイッ
Yummy...
おいしい！　甘い
Sweet!
Really, Jun, you're a born chatterbox.
順はホント　口から生まれてきたのね
ちょっと待ってね　今　パパのお夜食　作っちゃうから
Hold on a second.
I'm going to finish making
Daddy's late-night snack now.
そうっ　パパがね！　お城から出てきたの
Right! Daddy just came out of the castle!
お城？
- Castle?
- Yes! The one on the mountain!
うん　お山の！
パパ王子様だったの！
See, Daddy's a prince!
The princess wasn't you, but...
お姫様　ママじゃなかったけど
ママ　ご飯作ってたから　舞踏会　行けなかったの？
Did you miss the ball
because you were cooking?
あっ　もしかしてママ　魔女だったりするの？
Wait, could you be a witch, maybe?
でも　きっといい魔女ね　悪い魔女は　もっと…
But I bet you're a good witch!
Bad witches are more...
Jun...
順…
それ以上　しゃべっちゃダメよ
You mustn't say anymore.
Why not?
なんで…
You mustn't tell anyone about that.
それ　誰にも　しゃべっちゃダメ
もう二度と　しゃべっちゃダメ
Don't ever talk about it again.
もう…　二度と？
Not ever?
それじゃこれで全部ですね
All right, that's the last of it.
Please sign here.
こちらにサインお願いします
ああ　はい
Uh, right.
And so...
そして　おなかの出た王子様は　いい魔女にすみかを追い出され
the prince with the protruding gut
was banished from his home
by the good witch...
泣く泣くお姫様の元へ
and sent to the princess against his will.
Daddy...
Hey, where are you going?
ねっ　どこ行くの？
Uh, I'll be in the car, then.
じゃ　先　車乗ってるんで
ああ　お願いします
Right. Thank you very much.
Hey...
ねえ
あっ　あのね　ママとケンカしたんならね　順が仲直りさせてあげる
If you've had a fight with Mommy,
I'll help you make up!
So Daddy, you can just
stay here like always- -
だからね　パパは今までどおりに…
Jun.
順
You really are a chatterbox.
お前は…　本当におしゃべりだな
全部　お前のせいじゃないか
This is all your fault, don’t you see?
Thank you for waiting.
お待たせしました
All right, I'll lead the way.
じゃ　先導しますんで
あっ　お願いします
Right, thank you.
誰か…
Somebody, my prince...
順の王子様　今すぐここに　順を助けに来てちょうだい
Please come and rescue me
right this minute.
やあ　王子様だよ
Hey! I'm your prince.
Why are you an egg and not a prince?
どうして王子様じゃなくて　玉子なの？
But I am a prince! See?
王子様だよ
ほら　ここを隠すと…
If I hide this... You see?
My prince isn't all slippery like you,
and he doesn’t smell farty, either!
順の王子様はこんなツルツルじゃないし　おならのにおいもしない
いやぁ　なんたる口の悪さ
Oh, my, what a foul mouth!
You really are a chatterbox.
君は本当におしゃべりだな
A chatterbox?
Even an egg calls me that?
「おしゃべり」って　玉子まで順をそう言うの？
Because you're such a chatterbox,
君のこの先の人生
you'll be facing turmoil
and drama in the life ahead of you.
おしゃべりのために　波乱による波乱が待ち構えているだろう
Such a blabbermouth that you'll
fall victim to shady telemarketers.
おしゃべりすぎて怪しげな　キャッチセールスに引っかかり
Such a blabbermouth that you'll be fitted with
cement shoes and thrown into the sea!
おしゃべりすぎてコンクリで　固められ　海に沈められる
海に！?
In the sea?
そう　いいかい？
That's right. Listen up.
If you don’t want to lead that kind of life,
you've got to seal away your words.
そんな人生を歩みたくなければ　おしゃべりを封印するんだ
封印？
Seal?
Right.
そう
おしゃべりを　海に沈めることができれば
If you can sink your words into the sea,
君はキャッチセールスに　引っかかることなく
you won't ever get scammed
by a telemarketer.
You’ll get to meet a real prince,
and you'll get to go to a real castle!
本当の王子様に出会えて　本当のお城に行ける
Ream?
ホント？
で…でも　おしゃべり　やめられなかったら？
But what if I can't stop talking?
Then your prince, your castle.
All that will go up in smoke.
王子もお城も　全ておじゃんだ
Up in smoke?
おじゃん？
They'll really, truly, go up in smoke.
本当の本当に　おじゃんになっちゃうんだ
The yolk. The whites.
キミもシロミもゴッチャゴチャの　スクランブルエッグだ
Muddled together
like a mess of scrambled eggs!
No way!
そんな！
でも私　どうしよう　封印なんて…
But what should I do?
I can't seal--
All right.
よし
君のおしゃべりが治るように　口にチャックを付けてあげよう
To cure you of being so talkative,
I'm going to put a zipper
on your mouth.
Ziiiiiiiiip...
Naruse
No Junk Mail
The Anthem of the Heart
アイタ
玉子？
An egg?
Hey, kid! Kid!
おにいちゃん　おにいちゃん　拾って　拾って
Pick 'em up! Pick 'em up!
Words?
言葉？
ああ　ここに
Yeah. Right here.
Hey, thanks.
おう　ありがと
This particular god loves talking!
ここの神様はおしゃべりが　大好きなんだいな
Speak into eggs and fill 'em up
with all kinds of words.
こいつの中身に　こう　色マ　しゃべりかけてな
色んな言葉を詰めるんだってよ
Any words will do?
言葉って　どんなのでも　いいんですか？
That's right!
そう　いい女とヤリてえとか　あいつ殴りてえとか何でもな
Like "I wanna sleep with a hot woman,"
or "I want to bust that jerk." Anything!
Then, you hang them here,
and it'll be like an offering.
そいつをこうして捧げてやると　お供えの代わりになる
へえ　そうすると　どうなるんスか？
And what happens if you do that?
えっ？　ああ　まあ何かしら　ご利益があるんじゃねえけ？
Well, I guess there must be
some kind of benefit!
Vague, much?
アバウトっスね
おはよう
- Morning!
- Good morning!
おはよう
今日の課題やった？
- Did you prep for the class?
- Not yet.
ううん　まだ…
What's inside the egg?
So what did you end up doing?
んで　結局どうした？
Of course, I whacked his ass
with my bat!
まあ　そりゃもちろん　ケツバット　ドーン！
These uniforms are cute!
ここのユニフオーム　かわいい！
どれ？
Let me see.
ああ　ホント　色のバランスいいね　このロゴとか…
Yeah, the color balance is great.
Like this logo here...
Oh, right. I guess having
a great logo ties it all together.
あっ　そうだね　やっぱりロゴがいいと　全体が締まるっていうか…
Morning, Taku!
はよ　拓ちゃん　遅かったね
You got here late, huh?
うん　ちょっとな
- I got held up.
- Hey, not bad.
おお　いいじゃん　岩木も腕あげたな
Iwaki, you've totally outdone yourself!
You think?
そう？
拓　はよ
Taku. Morning!
All righty! How about we take our seats?
よース　席着いてみっか
Let's see...
えっと　こないだ決まらなかった　地域交流会の実行委員ね
Our unresolved issue,
the Community Outreach Committee.
We've reached our time limit on that.
あれ　もうタイムリミット
We're gonna decide on it now!
今決めまーす
In the first place,
why do we have to do it?
そもそもさ　なんで　あれ　うちらがやんの？
各学年で１クラスだけなんでしょ？
Only one class per grade, right?
I already did it when we
were first years, you know.
私　１年の時も当たったのに
まあまあ　細かいことは置いといて
Now, now, let's forget about small things.
やる気になってる人　いたら５秒以内に名乗り出ましょう
Anyone who has the motivation!
Announce yourselves in the next five seconds!
ウザー
- So annoying! - What's up with that?
- Five, four, three, two...
5 4 3 2
何だ　そりゃ
- Five, four, three, two...
One, zero. Okay, time's up!
１　ゼ口…
はい　終了
やっぱりね
Just as I thought.
Therefore!
…というわけで　決めてきました
I've already picked our committee.
えーっと…
Let's see...
Takumi Sakagami.
坂上拓実
成瀬順
Jun Naruse.
田崎大樹
Daiki Tasaki.
仁藤菜月
Natsuki Nito.
というわけで　よろしくな
COMMUNITY OUTREACH COMMITTEE MEMBERS TAKUMI SAKAGAMI
JUN NARUSE DAIKI TASAKI NATSUKI NITO So anyway,
COMMUNITY OUTREACH COMMITTEE MEMBERS TAKUMI
SAKAGAMI JUN NARUSE DAIKI TASAKI NATSUKI NITO
菜月　やんの？
You doing this, Natsuki?
えっ？　分かんない　何なのこれ
I don’t know.
What's going on?
- Like he said...
- You've got to be kidding me.
マジかよ
Shimaccho picked this year's
Outreach Committee himself.
今度のふれ交の委員を　嶋っちょがさあ
No way am I doing this.
やらねえっスよ　俺
おい　大ちゃん
Hey,Dai.
そういうのは　もっと暇そうなやつに　やらせときゃいいんじゃねえの？
Shouldn't you be assigning this
to the people who have no life?
Well, no.
いや　俺はね
I'm a teacher of extreme integrity,
so I don’t play favorites like that.
至極まっとうな　先生だから　そういうひいきはしないの
時間はみんなに　等しく分配されてんだからさ
After all, time is distributed
evenly among you all.
ミミズだって　オケラだって…
- Even the earthworms. Even the crickets.
- What're you getting at?
何が言いたいんスか？
やってね
Just do it, okay?
これ命令だから
That's an order, see.
Look...
あのさぁ　命令とかよ　何　勝手なこと言ってんだよ
What are you saying?
ちょっ！　大ちゃん
HEY'. nan.
I...
嫌…　で…
don’t want...
えっ？　成瀬？
Naruse spoke?
しゃべった
Hey, so she can talk!
あいつって　しゃべれるんだな
わ…　たし…　じ…　こっ…
To... be... on the... committee.
おお　おーい　成瀬？
Hey, Naruse?
- You went too far, Shimaccho!
- Poor kid!
かわいそう
どうすんだよ
What are we gonna do?
Hey, Sakazaki! Sakazaki?
あっ　おい　坂崎
坂崎って！
坂上だけど
It's Sakagami.
Sorry, I was close, though.
ああ　悪い　惜しかったな
Not that close.
惜しくねえよ
それよか　あとは頼んだぜ
Anyway, I'm leaving the rest to you!
- That was pretty wild earlier, huh?
- Right?
さっきのすごかったよな
だろ？
DTM Research Club
やめてよ　相沢！
Cut it out, Aizawa! Using Miss Mint
for such a vulgar song.
ミントさんで　そんな…　下品な曲…
何言ってんだよ
What are you talking about?
「伊勢崎町ブルース」っつったら　名曲だぞ　お前
Isezaki-cho Blues is a classic, you know.
青江三奈様にケンカ売ってんの？
You gonna pick a fight
with the great Mina Aoe?
_ Ao- _
- Right, Taku?
なあ？　拓
アンニュイだね　拓ちゃん
You look weary, Taku.
ふれあい交流会なんて　テキトーに流しゃいいじゃん
You should just blow off
the Community Outreach Committee.
どうせ客なんて　近所のじいさん　ばあさんくらいしか　いねえんだし
No one's gonna show up
but the old folks from the neighborhood.
人ごとだよな
Like it's not your problem.
It isn't our problem!
人ごとだもん
まあ　あの人選は青春チョイスだよな　荒波チョイス
But that selection of his.
He went for the passion of youth.
The throes of adolescence!
Right, right.
うんうん　自分の殻に閉じこもる　無気力な若者と
An apathetic youth,
locked up in his own shell.
A sulky high school baseball star with
shattered dreams, and an eternally silent girl.
夢破れて　やさぐれた高校球児に　終始だんまり無言女
俺　成瀬の声って　今日　初めて聞いたよ
You know, I'd never heard
Naruse's voice before today.
And also a straight-arrow girl
who always seems to be in charge.
で　まとめ役の優等生女子
In terms of personalities,
that's east, south, west, and north!
キャラ立ちのトン　ナン　シャー
ペ一
Ron!
ロン！
Shousuushi! (Little Four Happiness)
小四喜
マ　マ　マ…　マジっスか？
ペ一きた
- I did it!
- Are you serious?
I'm gonna go complain to Shimaccho.
俺　やっぱ嶋っちょに　文句言ってくるわ
ヤクマン！
- Oh, crap!
- It serves you right, Aizawa!
相沢ざまあみろ
そういや
Came to think of it.
That was the first time
I ever heard her voice, tau.
Got it!
しゃス！
Got it.
しゃース
おい！　声出てねえぞ　声！
Hey! I can't you hear you, slacker!
しゃース！
Damn that Shimaccho.
Who does he think he's dealing with?
ったく　嶋っちょの野郎　人のこと甘く見やがってよ
でもさ　菜月と一緒に実行委員とか
But being on the committee with Natsuki
might bring you two closer.
距離縮まっちゃうんじゃねえの？
縮まってどうすんだよ
What's that supposed to mean?
そりゃ野球部のエースと　チアの部長ったら
The captain of the cheering squad
always dates the ace. It's like a tradition!
歴代　付き合ってきたわけじゃん
今のエースは山路だろ
Yamaji is our ace now, remember?
あっ　ああ　いや　その…
Uh...
My bad.
悪い…
三嶋！
Mishima!
呼んでんぞ
They're calling you.
Okay, I'll be going!
じゃ　行くわ　大ちゃんも　あとでミーティング　出てくれよな
Come to the meeting later, okay?
なんか切ないよね
It's kind of painful, isn't it?
ああ　野球部
Oh, the baseball team?
甲子園とか　まあビミョーに　夢見れる位置だったからね
Well, since their dreams of the Nationals
weren't all that far-fetched.
大樹のおかげで　みんな浮かれちゃってたもん
Everyone was so pumped up,
thanks to Daiki!
Their goal was to get past the third round
of the summer preliminary tournament.
「夏の予選大会の3回戦突破」が　目標だったチームが
めきめき力をつけた　エース様のおかげで
And thanks to their ace,
who'd flourished into an elite talent,
甲子園出場も　狙えるかもなんてさ
they could feel as if they were
within striking distance of the Nationals!
Fall Regional Baseball Championships Rising Star, Daiki Tasaki (15) Collects
the Most Strikeouts in the Tournament It was such a crystal-clear dream, too!
分っかりやすいドリームだったのに
Summer Nationals Ageha High Fails to Become
Best 4 How tragic that he'd blow out his elbow?
まさか肘　やっちゃうなんて　超哀れ
How tragic that
he'd blow out his elbow?
Hey, don’t be like that.
Ikkun will be devastated.
そう言ってやるなよ　いっくん　ショックだろうよ
ITSUKI MISHIMA
"IKKUN"
違うよ　いっくんじゃなくて　哀れなのは私
All that practice
for the tournament went to waste.
大会用の練習　無駄になっちやったし
何やってんの？　休憩終わりだよ
What are you doing? Break's over!
あー　ごめん
- Sorry!
- We'll be right there!
今　行くわ
Music Room
すいません
こっちだって聞いたんだけど…
I heard he should be here.
失礼しま…
I'm coming in.
お…　何だ　これ？　嶋っちょ　自由すぎだろ
What's this?
As if this was his own place.
また玉子…
Eggs again?
What is this, Egg Day?
なんか今日は縁があるな
ちゃんと音　出るんだな
It works, huh?
Eggs, 999$
たまごー　たまごー
Let me offer them to the eggs
玉子にささげよう
Beautiful wards
Beautiful words 言葉をささげよう
These words
Let me offer them
たま…
To the eggs
Am I being overrun by visitors?
千客万来？
Naruse? What are you doing here?
成瀬？　なんで？
Naruse! You leaving already?
成瀬　もう行っちゃうの？
お？　すげえ　直訴状？
I'd like to decline
being a committee member.
Good for her!
やるなあ
If she can talk,
she should just tell you to your face.
しゃべれるんなら　直接　言やあいいのに
Well, yeah.
まあな
I'm here for the same reason, by the way.
俺の用件も　それと同じですよ
For real?
There's no way we can pull it off
with those members.
大体　あの面子で　できるわけないでしょ
Aside from Nito- -
仁藤はともかく…
Then give me some names.
People who could handle it.
じゃ　他に名前　挙げてよ　実行委員に向いてるやつ
人身御供　捧げりゃ　そいつに変えてやるからさ
Offer up some human sacrifices,
and I'll be happy to switch you out.
You're too nice!
やっぱ優しいな　お前
But that nature could be
your detriment.
でも損するよ　そういうの
And who's the cause of it?
損させてんの　誰ですか？
あっ　そういや　さっきの　よかったよ
By the way,
I really liked it.
That song you played.
弾いてた曲
That was just something random.
あれは別にテキトーに…
Around the World, right?
「Around　the　World」だろ？
Such an old movie.
I'm impressed you knew it.
古い映画なのに　よく知ってたな
Well...
まあ　ミュージカルとかそういうの　好きなのが近くにいたんで…
I used to be around someone
who was into musicals.
それ　いいかもな
That might be just the thing!
ミュージカル！
A musical!
ちょうどいいじゃん　ふれあい交流会
It'd be perfect for
the Community Outreach event!
Where did that come from?
なんで　そうなるんスか？
I'm a music teacher,
you know.
俺　一応　音楽教師だし
Recitations and choirs,
year after year.
毎年　朗読劇とか　合唱とか　なんか物足りなかったんだよね
They just don’t do it for me.
They're more than enough for us.
十分　足りますよ
ねえ　俺って諦め悪いんだけど
Well, I'm not one to give up easily!
He saw.
見られた
He saw right into my heart.
心の中を見られた
ただいま
I'm home.
Welcome back.
おかえり
That car...
あの車…
What are you doing?
何やってんの？
ああ　ブレーキがな　もう寿命かもな
Yeah, I think these brakes are history.
Then use mine.
じゃ　俺の使ってよ
学校に行くのに困るだろ
But don’t you need yours to get to school?
いいよ　別に歩けるし
It's fine. I can just walk.
You need to get to the hospital, right, Gramps?
祖父ちゃん　病院あるでしょ
I'm- -
ただい…
こちらは１年ごとに　見直しができますので安心ですよ
Yes, you can reevaluate this one every year,
so that should set your mind at ease.
After we're gone,
how will the money be paid out?
私たちが死んでからの　保障って　どうなるのかしら
No need to worry about that, either.
そちらもご安心ください　例えば　お孫さんが…
For example, when your grandchild- -
あら　たっくん　おかえり
Welcome home, Takkun!
Hello.
こんちは
こんにちは
Is this your grandson?
お孫さんですか？
Yes.
はい
お孫さんも揚羽なんですね
I see your grandson goes to Ageha, too.
あら　成瀬さんとこの　お嬢さんも？
Oh, so your daughter goes there
as well, Ms. Naruse?
えっ？　あ…　まあ…
Uh, yes.
Do you know her? Miss Naruse?
知らない？　成瀬さん
あ…　あの…
- Naruse?
- Uh...
成瀬？　成瀬って…
Do you mean Jun Naruse?
順ですか？
Yes.
ええ　ご存じなの？
Do you know her?
いや　名前くらいで
No, just by name.
Is that right?
そ…そう
Uh, by the way, under the plan
I just described, there's another perk...
あ　そういえば先ほどのプランですと
もう１つ　特典がありまして　こちらなんですが…
- This is it.
- Oh, yes.
If you add this feature,
こちらの特典をつけますと　こちらの保障がつきます
you'll receive this perk.
All right, I'll be leaving now.
それでは失礼いたします
She's raising her daughter
single-handedly! Isn't that admirable?
女手一つでお子さん育ててるんだって　偉いわね
Hey, this is good.
あっ　うまい
Ms. Naruse brought those over.
Cream red-bean pancake.
それ　成瀬さんから頂いたのよ　生どら
She's a cheerful little chatterbox, isn't she?
明るくて　おしゃべりなんでしょ
いつもお友達と　長電話して電話代がすごいって
Her mother says she's always on the phone
with her friends, so their phone bill's astronomical!
Uh, no...
あっ　いや…　そんな　プライべートなことまでしゃべんの？
You talk about private stuff like that?
あら　命を預ける人だもの
Well, we're putting our lives
in her hands, after all!
あら　お祖父さん　３つは食べすぎ…
Oh, no, dear. Three is too much!
あいつ　親父いないのか
So she doesn't have a dad, then?
# MUSIC OVER THE RAINBOW
Somewhere over the rainbow way up high
I'm sure you’ve all heard this at least once.
みんなも一度は聞いたことがあるだろ？　「Over The Rainbow」
Over The Rainbow.
There's a land that I heard of once in a lullaby
It's the huge hit number
from the movie, The Wizard of 0z.
ミュージカル映画「オズの魔法使い」の大ヒットナンバーだ
知ってる
- I know it!
- The one with the yellow brick road, right?
黄色のレンガのやつだよね？
そう　魔法の国に飛ばされた　主人公のドロシーが
That's right. Swept away to a
magical land, the heroine, Dorothy...
カンザスにある自分の家へ　何とか帰ろうとするっていう
does everything she can to return to
her home in Kansas. It's a simple story.
Somewhere over the rainbow skies are blue
シンプルな物語なんだが
In musicals, you convey your emotions
through songs, and you sing and dance to them.
ミュージカルってのは感情を　曲にのせて歌い　踊る
そうすると普通に表現するには　小っ恥ずかしい気持ちも
This makes it a breeze to communicate even
the feelings you're too shy to express normally.
And the dreams that you…
スルっと入ってくるんだよな
ってわけで今日は　この映画を　みんなで鑑賞しよう
So anyway, let's watch
this movie together today!
いや　やっぱないわ
Nope, doesn't exist.
The word "musical"
isn't in the Aizawa dictionary.
相沢ディクショナリーに　ミュージカル　載ってない
なんかこう　背中ザワザワするよね
It kind of sends chills
down your spine, doesn’t it?
Right, right.
そうそう　そのまましゃべればいいのに
They could just say the lines...
but then they burst into song.
That's what I don’t get.
急に歌になんのが謎なんだよなあ
まあ　でも　嶋っちょ　言ってたみたいに
Yeah, but like Shimaccho said,
歌だと何となく感情とか　分かりやすくしてくれるっつうか
maybe singing the lines
helps get your feelings across better.
You just uttered a gem, Taku!
拓ちゃん　なんか　いいこと言った
You've been poisoned by Shimaccho!
嶋っちょに毒されてんじゃん
It's not like that.
そんなんじゃねえよ
I see. So Tasaki's a no-show after all?
そっか　やっぱ田崎は来ないのか
I did remind him to come, but...
声はかけたんですけど
It's not a big deal.
いいじゃないスか　全部任せるって言ってたし
He told me he was leaving it all to us.
Let's just decide without him.
勝手に決めちゃいましょうよ
Not good...
いかんなぁ
This was supposed to be our
historic first committee meeting!
記念すべき　第１回目の実行委員会なのに
Well, as far as decision-making goes,
it's not like we have that many choices.
まあ　決めるって言っても　そんなに選択肢もないし
やっぱり合唱とか朗読とか
Maybe we should just
go with choir or recitations?
えーっ　それじゃ　いつもと一緒じゃん
What? But that would be
the same old, same old!
でも…
- But- -
But isn't that what people expect
of the Community Outreach event?
でも　ふれ交って　そういうものじゃないですか
As far as mingling with the community goes,
地域交流って言っても来るのは　近所のお年寄りくらいだし
no one really shows up
but the elderly who live nearby.
The elderly have pretty modern taste, you know!
お年寄りって結構　ハイカラ好きよ
Not making any changes, just sticking with
the status quo. How boring is that?
何にも変わらないで　ひたすら現状維持って　つまんなくね？
So? What are you getting at?
で　何が言いたいんスか？
You know as well as I do!
分かってるくせに
やっぱ今日の授業って…
You mean what we did in class today.
授業？
Class?
どう？　成瀬は？
What do you say, Naruse?
A musical?
ミュージカル
Mu...
ミュージ…
えっ？　成瀬？　大丈夫？
Naruse? Are you all right?
A musical?
What are we gonna do?
でもどうしよう　ミュージカルなんて
どうせみんな反対するだろうし
I bet everyone's
gonna vote against it.
今　考えることでもないんじゃない？
Let's not worry
about that now.
I guess not.
そうだね　じゃ明日のホームルーム…
Then tomorrow in homeroom,
let's let everyone- -
つか　田崎さん　マジ　ウゼぇんだけど
Jeez, that Tasaki's
such a pain in the butt!
Where does he get off,
bossing us around?
何偉そうにしてんだろうな
大事な時に　肘　ぶっ壊したポンコツのくせによ
He's a piece of junk who blew out his elbow
just when we needed him.
毎日　顔出して　文句ばっかつけやがって
Showing up everyday just to rip into us.
山路　お前からガツっと言ってくれよ
Yamaji, you set him straight!
やだよ　ほっときゃいいだろ　あんなの
Not me. Just ignore him.
でもよ…
- Yeah, but...
- Hey!
おい！　そろそろ外周　行くぞ
We're gonna head out to do some laps now!
Right!
ウースッ
今日何周っスか
I don’t like that kind of thing.
なんか…
５周
やだな　ああいうの
If they have something to say,
they should just speak up.
言いたいことあるんなら　はっきり言えばいいのに
Uh, I've got practice.
私　部活あるから先行くね
So I'll be going on ahead!
Okay.
Uh, I'm heading home now.
あの…
俺は　もう帰るけど
See you.
What's up with her?
何なんだよ　あいつ…
あの…
Listen...
Naruse, by any chance,
do you actually want to do a musical?
成瀬さ　もしかして　ミュージカルやりたかったりする？
えっ？何？
What?
Are you peeking
into my heart?
「私の…」
って…　何？　これ
What's this?
Don't pretend you don’t- -
しらばっくれ…　くっ…
Naruse?
成瀬？
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
Naruse?
成瀬？
So, "On my way home from school..."
そんで学校帰りに山の上のお城での　父親の不義密通…
"I saw my father commit adultery
at the castle on top of the mountain..."
And then an... an egg?
で　玉…　玉子？　に　しゃべるなと言われた　それで…
"Told me never to speak again. And so..."
The me who never speaks was born.
なるほど
Uh... "This is not fiction, but..."
えっとこれが　フィクションではなく…
A true story.
Though I did embellish it a little.
その…　城ってのはあれか？
The love hotel that used to be
on the mountaintop?
山の上にあったラブホ？
Right. Pretty mind-blowing.
そっか　すごいな
And I mean in a messed-up way.
基本はヤバイ意味で
Anyway, me peeking into your heart.
You've got the wrong idea, okay?
とにかく俺が心　のぞくとか　ホント誤解だから
That egg song the other day.
あん時の玉子の歌もさ
I was just randomly singing out a story
I heard from some old guy here.
ここでおっさんから聞いた話を
テキトーに歌っただけで
Look, don't you think
it's unproductive to do this by text?
あのさ
その…　メールで　やりとりするのって　不毛じゃないか？
それに…
- Besides- -
- Stomachache!
腹　つう…
What?
何？大丈…
Are you okay?
When I talk,
I get a stomachache.
When I talk, I get a stomachache.
I think that must be the curse.
そうなんだ
ホントに大丈夫か？
Are you sure you’re okay?
I think that must be the curse. Thank
you very much. I feel a lot better now.
そっか
Is that right?
Okay, I'm gonna head home now.
じゃ　俺はそろそろ行くわ
You be care- -
そっちも気を…
What you said today,
do you really believe that?
Do you think you can convey
your feelings better through song?
Are you talking about...
これって…
「ほうが」ってことは…
You're asking if it's better?
Well, singing, or music...
まあでも　歌ってか音楽って
もともと何かを伝えるためのものだと思うし
I think by nature,
it was always meant to convey something.
So Naruse, if there's something
you want to say...
成瀬もさ　伝えたいことあるんなら
don’t you think you should try singing?
歌ってみるのもありなんじゃね
Maybe singing
doesn't count for the curse.
歌ならさ　呪い　関係ないかもしれねえしって…
Hey!
What's up with that?
何だ？
My stomach's starting to hurt again.
I'm going home.
Been a long day.
See you tomorrow.
Oh, is it Naruse?
あら　成瀬さん？
Yes. The lights are on inside, but...
そうなの　明かりついてるんだけど
ああ　でもほら　ここって　あの娘さん…
Oh, but remember, the daughter here.
So Naruse, if there's something
you want to say...
成瀬もさ　伝えたいことあるんなら
Let me offer them to the eggs
玉子にささげよう
玉子に…ささげよう…
Let me offer them to the eggs
Beautiful words 言葉をささげよう
Beautiful wards
These wards
Let me offer them
My stomach doesn't even hurt!
おなかが　痛くない！
いくら朝練が自主参加っつっても
I know morning practice is optional, but still...
こんだけしか集まんねえって　何の冗談だよ
What's with this joke of a turnout?
わりい　大ちゃん
My bad, Dai.
やっぱ　俺が頼りねえから
It must be because I'm such a pushover.
んな話　してねえだろ
When did I ever say that?
でも…
- But- -
- You're...
お前は！
キャプテンとして　しっかりやってるよ
You're doing a great job as captain.
Dai.
大ちゃん
えー　とりあえず候補として　朗読　創作ダンス　民謡と舞踊
Here are our options.
Recitation.
Interpretive dance.
Japanese folk songs and dance.
Chorus.
合唱　アカペラ　合唱　演劇　英語劇
A cappella choir.
A play-
A play in English.
それと一応　今回のオリジナルとして…
And just for the heck of it,
as an original act...
a musical.
ミュージカル
以上のものを考えてみました
These are the choices we've come up with.
とりあえず　この中から…
So let's pick one of these and- -
えーっ　こん中から？
Out of these?
- What a drag.
- What did they do last year, again?
面倒だな
ミュージカルって　昨日見たみたいな？
Musical? You mean like
the one we saw yesterday?
ハードル高すぎだろ
Isn't that setting the bar too high?
何でもいいけど　簡単なのがいいし
I don’t care what we do,
as long as it's easy.
You got that right!
確かに
まあまあ　俺は悪くないと思うな　このアイデア
Now, now.
I don’t think it's half bad, this idea.
Rising to the challenge of something new.
That's an awesome feat!
新しいことにチャレンジするってのは　素晴らしいよ
新しいことってのは　内申にもいい影響が
- Not to mention, something new would look
darned good on your school record.
何が悪くないだよ　言い出しっぺが…
バカじゃねえの？
Are you people morons or what?
What do you mean, challenge?
何がチャレンジだよ
You know it's never gonna happen!
何も始める前から無理とか…
You don’t have to say it's impossible
before we even get started!
無理だろ　大体その女　どうすんだよ
But it is impossible!
In the first place,
what are we gonna do about that girl?
With a girl who can't even talk
on the committee.
実行委員にしゃべんねえ女いて
Singing, doing a musical.
You've got to be kidding!
そんで歌とかミュージカルとか　謎すぎんだろ
なあ？
Right?
Hey, Tasaki!
ちょっと田崎　あんた　何絡んでんの？
What's with all the taunting?
あ？　本当のことだろ？
But it's the truth.
Hey, Shimaccho!
なあ　嶋っちょ　そんな使えねえやつ　外して
Shouldn't we just get rid of that useless kid
and pick a new committee?
もっかい　委員　選び直したほうがいいんじゃね？
- Tasaki! That's enough.
- Who are you to call her useless?
田崎！　いい加減にしろ
使えねえのは　どっちだよ
あんた　どこでも一緒だな
You’re the same wherever you go.
Sakagami.
坂上君！
後輩君たちも　かわいそうに
- I feel sorry for the younger guys
on your team.
おい　大ちゃん
はあ？　何言ってんだ
What are you talking about?
The younger guys were complaining about you.
後輩君たち　愚痴ってたよ　使えないポンコツのくせに
"That useless piece of junk!"
Swaggering at practice every single day,
you’re a real thorn in their side!
毎日　偉そうに出張ってきて　すっげえ邪魔だってよ
Hey, Sakagami!
おい　坂上
You bastard. You’re so full of it!
てめえ　何　テキトーなこと言ってんだ
Ikkun?
いっくん！?
Shooting off your mouth like that
when you don’t know a thing.
何も知りもしねえくせに　勝手なことウダウダほざきやがって
What do you know about Dai, anyway?
てめえに大ちゃんの　何が分かんだよ
- Mishima! Calm down!
- Can't breathe...
三嶋　ちょっと落ち着け
Hey, cut it out!
What's your problem?
ねえ　やめてよ　何なの？
ちょっと離してくれよ
Let me go!
- No, I don’t think that would be wise.
そんなわけには…
おい　坂上
やめてつてば！
- Hey! Sakagami!
- I said cut it out!
ねえ！
- Come on!
- You did you just...
お前　さっき…
私は～　やれ～　るよ～
I can handle it!
Although I have anxieties,
I'm sure... that... I can...
不安は～
あるけど～
きっと…
で～　きる…
Naruse? Wait!
成瀬さん！？　ちょっと！
成瀬さんってば！
Naruse!
えっ？　何だ？　あれ
What was that?
- Wow.
- That was Naruse?
すげえ
成瀬さんだよね
これってミュージカルってやつ？
- Was that a musical?
- Out of nowhere!
三嶋
Mishima.
Sorry. I kinda lost it.
わり　ちょっとカッとなった
No...
あ　いや…　俺も　ちょっと言いすぎたし
I was out of line, too.
成瀬さん
Hey, are you sure you’re okay?
ねえ　本当に大丈夫？　やっぱり先生　呼んで…
に…　仁藤？
- Shouldn’t I get the teacher?
- Nito, are you in there?
その…　そこにいんの？
Is Naruse with you?
成瀬も一緒か？
- Is everything- -
- Sakagami.
だいじよ…
坂上君
おお　成瀬は？
Where's Naruse?
中　個室に閉じこもっちゃって
Inside.
She's locked herself in a stall.
Is this from...?
これって成瀬さん？
Naruse?
ああ　昨日ちょっとな
Yesterday, we just happened to- -
Sorry I went ahead
and said all that.
No, I'm sorry. I owe you one.
Does your stomach hurt?
- Does your stomach hurt?
- No, it doesn’t hurt.
- No, it doesn’t hurt. It's not hurting me.
- Does your stomach hurt? - No, it doesn't hurt.
It's not hurting me. - Just like you said, Sakagami,
when I sing, it doesn’t hurt.
I see. So that's what happened yesterday.
そう　昨日　そんなことあったんだ
That's why- -
それで…
But thank goodness
she came back to class after that!
でもよかった　あのあと　授業出てきてくれて
教室の雰囲気は　ビミョーだったけどな
Well, although things were
pretty awkward in that classroom.
まあね
Well, yes.
んじゃ　俺　部室で飯食うから
Okay, I'm gonna have lunch in my clubhouse.
Okay.
キレイな声だったね　成瀬さん
Naruse had a beautiful voice, huh?
何となく気持ちは　分からなくもないんだ　あいつの
I kind of get
where she's coming from.
There are things that I
can't say either, even if I want to.
俺も言いたいのに言えないこととか　やっぱ　あるから
Right.
ワタシハ　ヤレルヨ
...can handle it!
That song Naruse sang today.
I recreated it.
今日　成瀬が歌ったやつ　ちょっと作ってみたんだ
フアンハ　アルケド
Why?
なんで？
成瀬さんの聞いて　ピンときたんだよね
After hearing Naruse,
it clicked, right?
キット　デキル
そっ　ＤＴＭで　ミュージカルっぱいのってありだなって
Right. That musical-ish DTM
could work, too.
ワタシハ　ヤレルヨ
It might even be cool to set
manga dialogue to music, huh?
漫画のセリフとかに曲つけても面白そうだよね
Hey, sounds good!
おっ　いいな　ハンターやろうぜ　ハンター
Hunter! Let's do Hunter!
なんかべタじゃね？
フアンハ…
- Kinda cliché, don’t you think?
- Not really!
Dai!
大ちゃん
Hey.
Dai... You coming to practice today?
大ちゃん　その…　今日は部活は…
Sorry.
悪い　ちょっと用事があるんだ
I have something to take care of.
もし坂上が言ってたこと　気にしてんなら　あんなの…
If what Sakagami said got to you.
That was nothing but--
ちげえよ
That's not it.
I really do have an errand to run.
I already let Coach know.
ホントに用事あんだよ　監督にも言ったし
IS that right? Then- -
そ…　そっか　じゃ…
Ikkun!
いっくーん
I'll be waiting for you after practice
at the convenience store again!
今日も終わったら　コンビニで待ってるからね
陽子　早く行くよ
- Yoko, come on!
- Right!
Hey, don’t be jealous!
もう　妬かないでよ
Who, me?
誰が？
See ya.
今日の坂上　もしかして菜月に　いいところ見せたかったのかな
Hey, you think Sakagami
was showing off for Natsuki today?
Well...
いや　俺あの２人と同中なんだけど　中学ん時…
I went to the same junior high with them.
Back then...
- I'm starving!
- Let's stop by the convenience store!
ああ　腹減った
コンビニ寄ろうぜ
Oh, man, miso potatoes!
ミソポテト食おう　ミソポ
Oh, no! It's already here!
ヤバ　もう来てる
なんで乗らねえの？
Why didn't you get on?
What about you?
In a place like this.
そっちこそ何してんの？
こんな所で
If I get home too early,
my mom will freak out.
あんま早く帰っと　母ちゃん　ビックリするからな
When I'm not playing baseball,
it's like time has stopped.
野球やんねえと　時計が止まってるみてえだ
Hey...
なあ　お前も暇なら付き合えよ
If you’re free, hang out with me.
Wanna go to that castle
on the mountain with me?
俺と山の上の城にでも行かね？
Castle?
城？
But that's a love hotel!
As if I'd go there!
あれって　ラ…　ラブホじゃない！行くわけないでしょ
Anyway, it went out of business last year...
てか　あそこ去年　潰れたって
You sure know a lot about it.
よく知つてんな
That's because I heard everyone
talking about it!
そっ　それは　みんなが言ってたから
Go out with me.
付き合えよ　俺と
I told you...
だから！
ダメ　私　付き合ってる人いる
I can't. I'm seeing someone else.
えっ！？　誰？
Who?
That's a secret.
内緒
Then how long were you with Sakagami?
んじゃ　坂上とは　どんくらい付き合ってたん？
Did you go to that castle with him?
あいつとは城　行ったりしたんか？
We've never even held hands.
手もつないだことないよ
Actually...
っていうか…
I don’t even know his email address.
メアドも知らない
And you call that dating?
それで付き合ってたって　言えんのかよ
What does it matter?
もういいでしょ
Where are you going?
どこ行くんだよ
The bus.
バス　次の電車まで　３０分以上あるし
The next train won’t come for over 30 minutes.
If you want to kill time, then help us
with the Community Outreach event.
時間
もし潰したいなら　ふれ交　手伝ってよ
It looks like we'll have
our work cut out for us.
準備も大変そうだし　時間　いっぱい潰せると思うよ
You can kill lots of time.
Dammit...
クッソ…
あら　また成瀬さん？
Oh, is it Naruse again?
Yeah, what should I do?
そう　どうしようかしら
Should I tell the chairman...
今度　町内会長に言って…
Well, well!
あら
Right, duly paid!
はい　確かに今月の町内会費　頂きました
Confirming receipt of this month's
block association dues.
Your mother's always late
getting home, isn't she?
お母さん　いつも遅いのね
Isn't this a rough time
for the insurance industry?
保険って今　大変なんでしょ？　入る人少なくて
With so few people buying policies.
あっ　そうだ　順ちゃん　学校はどう？
Oh, by the way...
How's school, Jun?
うちの子来年受験でしょう？
My kid's taking the entrance exams
next year, you know?
順ちゃんとこの学校　どうかなって…
And I was wondering
about your school, Jun.
こんばんは　あの…
Good evening.
Uh...
ああ　おかえりなさい　いえねえ　町内会費を…
Welcome home!
You see, I came for the
block association dues.
ああ　すみません
I'm sorry.
最近　忙しくて　えーと…
I've been so busy lately.
ああ　もう頂きましたから
I've already collected them.
じゃあね　順ちゃん
See you, Jun!
Good night, then.
それじゃ　お邪魔しました
ええ　ご苦労さまです
Thank you for your hard work.
お母さんがいない時は出ないで　みっともない
Don't answer the door if I'm not here.
It's disgraceful.
しゃべらない子って色んな所で　噂になってて　もう…
A child who doesn't speak. There are
rumors all over the place. Really, now...
あ…　車
Oh, the car.
順！
Jun!
ちょっと　どこ行くの？
Hey, where are you going?
もう…
Let's see. Light bulbs, yogurt...
えっと　電球　ヨーグルト…
よし
All right.
If she sings, huh?
「歌だったら」か…
何だ　こりゃ　長っ！
What's this?
It's super-long!
また…
Another one?
えっと…
Um...
ゲッ…　ちょっと待てよ
Hold up a second!
えっと…
Uh... What's going on here?
わっ…　何なんだ　一体
Please turn my words into song.
言葉を…
Words, into song?
歌に？
訳　分かんねえ
I don’t get it.
あの！
Excuse me!
Excuse me.
あの…　玉子の歌みたいにしてほしいんです
I want you to do what you did
with that egg song!
成瀬？
Naruse?
私の気持ち…
My feelings...
What I really want to say!
ホントに…　しゃべりたいこと！
Into a beautiful...
ステキな…　う…　歌に…
song...
おい！　成瀬！?
Hey!
Naruse!
なあ　拓実は？
Hey...
Where's Takumi?
お買い物　電球　買いに行ってもらったの
Out shopping-
I asked him to go get some light bulbs.
The one in the bathroom went out.
おトイレの切れちゃって
At this hour?
こんな時間にお前何でも　拓実に頼むの　やめなさいよ
Stop asking Takumi to do everything!
だって　ちょっと手が離せな…
I was in the middle of something- -
Come on.
ほら　こっちだよ　足元　気いつけてな
It's this way.
Watch your step, okay?
Takumi?
拓実？
Hey...
挨拶はいいから
Forget the pleasantries!
そこの突き当たり
It's at the end of the hall there.
友達か？
Is that a friend?
えっ？　ああ　うん…　かな？
I guess?
おい！　電球　トイレ！　ちょっと待ってろ
Hey! The light bulb!
In the bathroom!
Hold up a sec!
The young girl who likes daydreaming
yearns to attend the nightly ball at the castle.
「夢見がちな少女は　白で毎夜　行われている舞踏会に憧れる」
But this ball...
「しかし　その舞踏会は…」
「しかし　その舞踏会は　実は罪人たちの処刑場だった」
But this ball...
was actually an execution site for criminals.
「彼には罪を償うため　死ぬまで永遠に　踊り続けなければいけないという」
They are condemned to atone for their sins...
by dancing forever, until they die.
Such a curse has been cast upon them.
「呪いがかけられていたのだ」
その真実を知ってもなお　舞踏会へ行きたい少女は
Despite knowing the truth,
the young girl, still wanting to go to the ball,
begins to commit all kinds of crimes.
様々な犯罪を重ねる
However...
しかし　それらは誰にも罪に問われることはなかった
nobody ever charges her with those crimes.
絶望する少女の前に　謎の玉子がやってきて　そそのかす
There, a mysterious egg appears
and incites the girl in despair.
Telling her,
"The most egregious sin in this world...
この世界で最も重大な罪は「言葉で人を傷つけることなのだ」と
is to hurt others with your words."
The girl begins spouting
every abusive word she can think of...
少女は考えつくだけの悪口を言いまくり
hurting others...
人を傷つけ　人に嫌われ　そして気がつくと…
earning their dislike...
and the next thing she knows...
She's lost the ability to speak.
「言葉を失ってしまいました」と…
I wrote it based on
what had happened to myself.
なんか物騒になってるけど…
This is kind of disturbing, you know.
So what happens in the end?
で　これ最後どうなんの？
This is all I have so far,
and I haven't come up with the ending yet.
What she really wants to say, huh?
「本当に　しゃべりたいこと」か…
こんばんは　これ　よかったらどうぞ
Good evening!
Please help yourself, if you like!
成瀬さんの　娘さんですってねえ
I hear you’re Ms. Naruse's daughter!
My, but you do have the same exact eyes!
あら　ホント目元なんかソックリ　やっぱり女の子は…
Well, girls are--
祖母ちゃん　上の部屋　ちょっと使ってもいいかな
Grams, is it all right if we
use the room upstairs?
What? Yes...
えっ　ええ　そりゃもちろん
Well, of course you can.
This is my dad's room.
ここ　親父の部屋なんだ　音楽が趣味でさ
His hobby is music.
それで俺も　やりたくもないのに　ピアノとか習わされて…
So even though I didn't want to,
he made me learn how to play the piano.
あっ　その辺　座って
You can sit here.
Grams, huh?
祖母ちゃんか
ここ　ミュージカルの曲も結構あってさ
There are a bunch of show tunes in here, see.
Like what I did with that egg song.
例の玉子の歌もそうだけど
I can't write songs from scratch, so...
俺　一から作曲なんて　できないからさ　ありもんの曲に
we can just stick some lyrics
into existing songs.
テキトーに歌詞はめてって…
うーん例えば…
For example...
this part from that email you just sent me.
さっき　もらった　メールのこの辺を…　えっと…
Let's see.
At the glittering golden castle
きんぴかのお城で　夜ごとくりかえす
Night after night, it happens
Attended by gentlemen and ladies
紳士と淑女つどう　あの舞踏会
That ball
Something like that.
みたいな？
おっ　大げさだな
That's overkill!
歌詞はお前のだろ！
The lyrics are yours, remember?
My bad.
悪い
The thing about you, Naruse...
いや　成瀬ってさ　歌わなくても　考えてること　丸分かりだよな
Even if you don’t sing, you display exactly
what you’re thinking.
だから　そういうのがだよ
See?
That's what I'm talking about!
Hey...
なあ　本当に迎えに来てもらわなくて　よかったのか？
Are you sure you don’t need to get picked up?
I see.
そっか
We should talk to Nito
about this tomorrow.
明日　ちゃんと仁藤にも相談しなきゃな
ふれ交でミュージカルやりたいって
That we want to put on a musical
for the Community Outreach event.
So be sure to finish that story, okay?
だから話　ちゃんと最後まで書いてな
成瀬のホントにしゃべりたいことっての　ちゃんと話にしなよ
Turn what you really want to say into a story.
えっ？　これから？
NOW?
Yeah.
ああ　もちろん部活　終わってからで　いいんだけど
You can come after practice, of course.
まあ　今日は体育館　使えないから
Since we can't use the gym today,
we should be done early...
早めに終わると思うけど
Then we'll be waiting for you at the diner.
じゃ　俺ら　ファミレスで待ってるから
Text me if you’re running late.
じゃ 遅くなるようなら　メールして
See you.
1 den '1' even knew your email address!
メアド　知らないんだってば！
今日も駅で暇潰し？
Killing time at the station again today?
Sarcastic, much?
嫌味な女だな
だったらさ…
If that's the case...
Were you nervous there?
緊張したか？
Before we head to the diner,
I want to stop by somewhere.
ファミレス行く前に　ちょっと寄りたいとこ　あるんだけど
What the hell, man?
I thought you had no interest in 3D!
何だよ　お前　３次には興味ないんだろ？
Voice actors are 2.5D!
声優さんは２．５次元！
This is it.
ここなんだけど…
何やってんの？
What are you doing?
DTM Research Club
ワタシハ　ヤレルヨ
Jeez, if you’re bringing a girl here,
let us know in advance!
ったく　女子連れてくるんなら　ちゃんと前もって言えよな
フアンハ　アルケド
What's up with that?
何だよそれ
ごっ　ごめんね　成瀬さん　勝手にこんなことして…
Sorry, Naruse!
For doing this without telling you.
キット　デキル
Does that mean you don’t mind?
大丈夫ってこと？
Thank God.
よかった
Listen,
あのさ　お前ら　俺がふれ交で本気でミュージカルやるって言ったら
what if I was serious about doing
a musical for the Community Outreach event?
どうする？
えっ　めんどくさい
A pain in the ass.
普通に　やだな
I totally don’t like the idea.
But if you’re serious, I'm in.
まあでも　拓が本気ってんなら　付き合うよ
I do want to hear
Naruse sing some more.
成瀬さんの歌　もうちょっと　聞いてみたいしね
おっ？　何　告白？
Is that a confession of love?
Of course it's not!
ワタシハ　ヤレルヨ
ばっ！？　なわけないでしょ　僕のハーレムは　すでにいっぱいで
ったく
- Jeez...
- My harem's already full!
There's no room for
a 3D girl to squeeze in!
３次の介入する隙なんて　ないんだよ
Gotcha. Your harem?
分かった分かったって　ハーレムって何？
We've already got one song.
この前ので１曲　時間も限られてるから　歌は多くても6曲くらいかな
Within the time frame,
the most we can fit in is six songs?
And then- -
あとは…
ごめん　お待たせ
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Oh, he looked totally available, so...
ああ　暇そうだったから　田崎君だって一応　委員だし
Tasaki is on the committee, after all.
So what did you want to talk about?
それで話って？
Oh, the thing is...
ああ　実は…
Uh, is this...
えっと　これって
A story that Naruse wrote.
成瀬が書いた物語
Naruse wrote it?
成瀬さんが？
話ってのは　それを今度のふれ交で
We wanted to tell you...
we want to adapt this story
into a musical for the Outreach event.
ミュージカルとして　やりたいってことなんだけど
ああ　やるのって　オリジナルなんだ
So we're putting on an original work.
But this story...
でも　このお話…
ああ　まだラストまでは決まってなくて…
Oh, the ending isn't done yet.
でも　いいのか？
But are you okay?
いや　ミュージカルやるってこと
With putting on a musical?
それは…　だって昨日の成瀬さん見たら…
Yeah...
After seeing Naruse yesterday.
そっか　んじゃ　田崎は？
I see. And Tasaki?
成瀬
Naruse...
その…　何だ　きっ　昨日は
Uh... You know...
About yesterday- -
やっぱ田崎さんいねえと　サボんの楽な！
Ditching practice is a piece of cake
without Tasaki around!
なあ　いやマジでさ　このままずっと来んなっつの
Yeah, seriously.
I wish he'd stop coming for good!
- The second years are all slacking off.
- Four drink bar, please.
あっ　ドリンクバー　人数分で
2年もみんなダレてっし　マジ意味ねえよ
あっ　はい　それではカップはあちらにご用意してますので
- Cups are over there.
- There's no point. Right, Yamaji?
なあ　山路
ああ　はいはい　了解っス
- Yeah.
- Okay. Can we have one menu?
あっ　一応メニュー１つもらえます？
三嶋さんもピリッとしねえし
- Mishima's pretty ineffectual.
かしこまりました
こんなんで　うちのチーム　どうなんの？　ったくよ
なあなあ　ポテトいっちゃう？
- What's gonna happen to our team?
- Shall we get potatoes? Potatoes!!
ポテ…　トーッ！
はっ？何？
What?
T-Tasaki...
たっ　たた　田崎さ…　先輩！
What do you think you’re doing?
おい　何やってんだ？　お前ら
Sorry!
さーせんしたっ！
何　勝手に頭下げてんだ
Who asked you to apologize?
俺に頭下げても何にもならねえだろ
Apologizing to me won’t cut it.
三嶋がどんだけ苦労してるかも　知らねえで
Not even realizing
what Mishima's going through.
What the hell do you think you’re doing?
てめえら　一体　何やってんだ
そりゃこっちのセリフっスよ
Right back at you.
Yamaji! Knock it off!
山路　やめろ
先輩こそ　何やってんスか
What are you doing?
部に顔も出さねえで　女連れて
Not showing up at practice,
taking some girl out...
You’re wrong about that!
ちっ　違うよ　私たちは学校の　そのふれ交の打ち合わせで…
We're here to discuss
the Community Outreach event...
ふれ交？
Outreach?
何が言いてえんだ　山路
Just spit it out, Yamaji.
When the new team
hasn't even gelled yet,
新チーム始まって　まだ体制の　固まってねえ　この時期に
ホント余裕っスね
you really are laid-back.
何が「今のエースはお前だ」だよ
What do you mean, "You’re our ace now?"
いっつもいっつも偉そうなことばっか言いやがって
All you ever do is throw your weight around!
目障りなんだよ
You’re an eyesore!
どうせなら俺の前からスッキリ　消えてくれりやいいのによ
I wish you disappeared
from my sight!
いっ　いい加減に…
Cut it...
いい加減にしろ！
Cut it out!
Don't tell people to disappear
like it's nothing!
消えろとか　そんな簡単に言うな！
こっ　言葉は傷つけるんだから！
Words can hurt people!
You can't ever...
絶対に…　もう取り戻せないんだから！
You can't ever take them back!
Even if you regret,
you can never take them back!
後悔したって　もう絶対に取り戻せないんだから！
Naruse?
成瀬　いいのか？
Are you okay?
何がっ！?
About what?
何がってその…
About...
「玉子の呪い」とかいうの…
That egg curse...
成瀬さん　大丈夫？
Naruse, are you all right?
- Is she okay?
- A doctor! No, an ambulance!
大丈夫スか？
医者？
いえ　救急車
成瀬！?
はい！　どうすんだっけ？
What do we do?
Phone! Cell phone!
でっ　電話！　携帯！
１１４だっけ？　１１６？
おっお客様　他のお客様にご迷惑が…
- Was it 114? - Excuse me, you’re
disturbing the other customers.
- Excuse me, you’re disturbing
the other customers.
おい　しっかりしろ　成瀬
いいから急げ！
Sorry, it's an emergency!
いや　それどころじゃねえんですよ
成瀬さん
Shimonita Hospital
Jun!
順！
I get a call from the hospital
and rush over, only to find...
病院から電話かかってきて　慌てて来てみれば
What do you mean, a stomachache?
何？　腹痛って…　また呪いとか何とかってやつなの？
Is this that curse thing again?
あっ　あの…
Excuse me...
This can't get any worse.
最悪…
Okay, you’re all set.
Please take care.
はい　結構です　ではお大事に
どうもありがとうごさいました
- Thank you very much.
- Oh, no! I've got to get going.
ヤバ…　私そろそろ行かないと
OK. Let's tell Naruse--
ああ　じゃ成瀬に一言…
Listen.
あのよ…　悪かったな　色々…
My bad.
It wasn't your fault--
別に田崎君のせいじゃ…
No, I- -
いや　俺は…
Why do you do this?
なんでなの！?　そんなに私が憎いの？
Do you hate me that much?
Never saying a word!
ずっと黙って…　近所の人に噂されて…
The neighbors always gossip about you.
順は何がしたいの？　私への嫌がらせ？
What are you trying to do?
Are you doing this to spite me?
何か言ってよ　反抗するならしてよ
Say something, will you?
Be rebellious if you want to.
I don’t understand.
分かんないの　もう！
I... I'm so tired!
もう疲れた
Of my job. Of the way you are. All of it!
仕事も順のことも全部！
You’re Sakagami's...
あなた　坂上さんの？
Uh... Naruse - Jun - is a cheerful kid.
あの…　成瀬…
順さんは明るいやつです
おしゃべりじゃないけど　何つうか　その…
She's not a chatterbox,
but... well...
She talks a lot inside her soul!
心の中では　いっぱいしゃべってるっつうか
The reason she got sick today...
今日　具合が悪くなったのも　俺たちの…
was because she pushed herself
too hard for our friend. So...
友達のためにムチャしてくれたからで　その…
I don’t know...
何つうか
何つうかばっかですけど　あの…
I know I keep saying I don’t know, but...
I just want to say that
Naruse is always really...
ただ成瀬は　いつも…　ずっと　ちゃんと頑張ってるんです
She's doing her best!
なんか驚いちゃった
You know, I was pretty surprised.
何が？
About what?
About all kinds of things.
何か色マ
なあ本当によかったのか？　ミュージカル
Hey, are you sure you're okay
with doing a musical?
I think I understand
how Naruse feels, too, so...
私も成瀬さんの気持ち　分かる気がしたから
Because there were things
I wanted to say and couldn't, either.
私にも言いたいのに言えないこと　あったから
Back in junior high,
中学の時…　坂上君が一番　大変だった時に
when you were going through
the hardest time of your life,
I couldn’t do anything for you.
私　何にもしてあげられなくて…
Even though I was your girlfriend.
彼女だったのに…
Even so...
それなのに…
Are Natsuki and Sakagami going out?
N-No...!
What Naruse said back there.
さっきの成瀬さん「言葉は　傷つける」ってグサっときた
That words can hurt.
That really hit home.
That was typical
junior high kid behavior.
そんなの　中坊なんてそんなもんだし
俺　つまんないやつで　もともと仁藤と　釣り合い　取れてなかったし
I'm such a boring guy.
I was never a good match for you.
That's not true!
そんなことない！　坂上君　どんな時でも絶対　弱音吐かなくて
You never whine, no matter what,
すごく気配りがあって　困ってる人のこととか　ちゃんと気づけて
you’re so considerate.
You always notice
when someone’s in trouble.
And also...
それに…
Thanks.
どうも
You’re welcome.
どういたしまして
No, but...
いや　でも…　うん…
俺　つまんない自分に　納得しちゃってたんだよな
I was okay with being a boring guy, you know.
思ってること言うのも　何か言われて　言い返すのも　なんか疲れるし
It was tiring to express my feelings
or argue back to someone.
Clashing with others was a pain,
so I was like, whatever.
周りとぶつかんのも面倒だし　どうでもいいやって
But Naruse...
でも成瀬がさ
Even though she was suffering,
あんなにつらそうなのに
she tried so hard to somehow express
the words inside her head.
それでも何とか　自分の中の言葉を表に出そうとして頑張ってんの見たら
When I saw that, I thought I...
What am I saying?
なんか俺も…
って　何言ってんだろうな
Well, I guess I mean that
I want to cheer her on!
まあ　応援したくなるっつうか…
って　あれ？
Sakagami, you have feelings for...
坂上君は成瀬さんのこと…
What's wrong?
どうした？
I'm going to cheer her on,
and you too, Sakagami!
私も応援する　成瀬さんのことも　坂上君のことも！
はあ？　なんで俺？
Why me?
Because you’ve stirred up
the cheerleader in me!
チアリーダーの血が騒ぐからに　決まってるでしょ
What's that about?
何だ？　そりゃ
- Being able to talk to Nita like this again...
仁藤とまたこんなふうに話ができてるのも　成瀬のおかげなんだよな
ああ　おなか減った
早くいこう　明日から忙しくなるね
- Boy, I'm starved! Let's get going!
- I have Naruse to thank for that, too.
You think so?
どうかな
So you do have friends.
友達がいたのね
The block association dues.
Thanks for that.
町内会費　ありがとね
成瀬は　いつも…　ずっと　ちゃんと頑張ってるんです
Naruse is always really... She's doing her best!
The prince bestowed upon the young girl,
who'd filled herself with sorrowful words,
王子様は悲しい言葉で　その身を満たした少女に
砂漠にしみていく水のような　とても尊い　幸せな言葉をあげたのです
extremely precious words of bliss,
like water seeping into the desert.
I missed out on my chance to apologize.
結局　謝り損ねたな
それで…
- What's wrong?
- He glared at me something fierce!
どうしたの？
なんかメッチャ　にらまれたんだけど
- What? Maybe he's into you, Aki!
- That would be terrifying!
えー　亜紀に気があるんじゃん？
いや　怖すぎっしょ
Jeez...
ったく　朝練サボりまくってたやつが　たまに来たら　これだよ
The guy who routinely ditches
morning practice finally shows up,
and this happens.
Sorry.
さーせん
The others are already in the gym. Hurry over.
もうみんな体育館　行ってっから　急げよ
Right.
ウス
Huh? Dai!
あれ？　大ちゃん
あっ　練習なら体育…
We have practice in the gym...
I'm sorry about everything till now!
今まで悪かった
は？　何…
Wha- -
試合もケガも全部　俺が…
- The game, my injury... that's all on me.
- Hold up, Dai!
待てよ　大ちゃん　そんなの大ちゃんだけのせいじゃ…
- It's not all on you...
- I know.
分かってる
But the thing is, I've got to do this
or we'll never get anywhere.
けどよ　こうしねえと始まらねえんだ
Even though I'm such a bonehead,
俺　頭わりぃのによ　全部1人で背負ってる気になって
I was thinking
I was the only one carrying the load.
Bossing you all around,
saying it's for the sake of the team.
偉そうなこと言って　そんでチームのためとか言って
But the truth is, I was shoving it all on you,
Yamaji, and the other guys as much as I could.
けど　本当は三嶋にも山路にも　他のやつらにも
おっかぶせるだけ　おっかぶせてた
But that's because I'm not a good captain.
そんなのキャプテンの俺が　しっかりしてねえから
That's not true.
違うんだ　そういうことじゃなくてよ
It's not about that.
If I keep this up,
everything about me is half-baked.
このままじゃ　俺　全部　中途半端なんだよ
みんな色んなこと　歯食いしばって耐えてんのに
Even though you guys are clenching
your teeth and taking it.
俺だけ謝って楽になろうなんて　虫がよすぎるってのは分かってる
I know it's selfish of me to just apologize
and be the one without a burden!
けどよ　ここで一度　仕切り直させてくれねえか
But can't you let me
start over right here, right now?
Yamaji...
山路…
Start over how?
仕切り直して　どうすんスか
Get healed up and shoot for the Nationals
again with you guys.
ケガ治して　もう一度お前らと　甲子園を目指す
俺　練習行きます
- I'm going to practice.
- Yamaji!
山路…
So what are you gonna do now?
で　これからどうすんの？
とりあえず　目の前のことを　１コずつ片付けてくわ
I'm gonna start by dealing with
everything I can now, one by one.
そっか
I see.
Really, I'm overcome with joy!
いやぁ　俺はうれしいよ
If you yearn so much to put on a musical,
then I'll throw my full support!
お前らがそこまで　ミュージカルがやりたいってんなら
俺　全力でバックアップするから
Like it wasn't your idea.
自分で言い出したくせに
Now if Tasaki would show up,
we'll all be here.
これであとは田崎が来れば　全員集合　怖いもんなしだな
We've got nothing to fear!
That's one thing
that's probably not gonna happen.
さすがにそれは　難しいんじゃないですかね？
何言ってんの
What are you talking about?
No matter the time or place, when it comes
to musicals, a miracle always seems to happen.
古今東西ミュージカルってのは　たいてい奇跡が起きるもんなんだよ
I wouldn't bet on- -
そんなわけ…
Excuse me.
失礼します
Hey, what's this?
ちょっと何？
成瀬…
Naruse...
この前は　ひでえこと言って悪かった
Sorry I trashed you the other day!
そんで　よければお前らの　やろうとしてるやつ　俺にも手伝わせてくれ
If you don’t mind,
let me help make this thing happen.
ダメか？
Is that a no?
T-Tasaki.
たっ　田崎君？
Of course! Thank you very much!
おっ　おう…　こっちこそよろしく
I'm looking forward to working with you, too.
What's going on?
何これ…
See? It did happen, right? A miracle!
起きたじゃん　奇跡
So anyway, at this year's Outreach event...
ってわけで
今度のふれ交で　今　配ったプリントの　ミュージカルをやります
we're going to put on
a musical based on that handout.
What's up with that?
何それ
なんで　いきなり！
Why so sudden?
ちょっと勝手すぎませんか？
Isn't that a bit much?
てか　この前はあんたが　一番　反対してたんじゃん
You were against this
more than anyone!
だよね
I know, right?
そうだよ
That's right.
I totally blasted Naruse,
俺は成瀬にひでえ難癖つけて
ミュージカルなんて　できっこねえって反対した
saying we could never pull off a musical.
けど　成瀬はできるって証明しただろ
But Naruse proved that we could, didn't she?
だからやるんだよ
So we're gonna do it.
でも　それって　田崎だけの問題じゃん
But that's just your own personal issue, Tasaki.
うちら　巻き込まないでほしいよね？
I wish you wouldn't drag us into it.
ちょっと…
Wait...
大体　なんで一番　めんどくさそうなミュージカル？
Why musical anyway?
It's the most complex option.
それに　これって　オリジナルやるってことだよね？
And this is an original work, right?
ふれ交まで　あと1か月ちょいしかないだろ？
We've only got a month and a bit
before the Outreach event.
ふれ交なんて　どうせ近所の人が　ちょっと来る程度だし
And only a handful of people from
the neighborhood show up.
Right. That's why we should
do something simpler.
そうだよ　だからもっと簡単なのをさ…
True...
確かに
At first, I didn't really care either,
to be honest.
俺も最初は　正直　どうでもいいと思ってた
But...
けど　1人でも本気のやつがいるんなら　そいつに乗っかって
If even one of us is ready to go all-in,
it'd be cool to ride on their coattails
and pull out all the stops to get it done.
必死こいてやってみるのも　面白いんじゃないかって思ったんだ
私も…
Me, too. We don’t have much time,
and it might be a lot of work,
その…　時間もないし　大変かもしれないけど
実行委員として　精一杯やるから　だから…
but as committee members,
we'll do everything we can!
いいじゃん
So why not?
If we do something,
the more extravagant, the better!
やっぱ　どうせやるなら派手なほうがいいし
Besides, this looks kind of interesting!
それに　これ　なんか面白そうだし
私も！ミュージカルならダンスとかもあるよね
I agree. There are dance numbers
in musicals, right?
I've been wanting to try
my hand at choreography.
振り付けとかやってみたかったんだ
江田っち…
Edacchi..."
拓
Taku! You’re gonna let us
handle the songs, right?
曲は俺たちが　やっていいんだよな？
ＤＴＭ研の晴れ舞台だね
This will be the DTM Club's day in the sun.
音楽周りはもちろん俺のほうでも　サポートするぞ
Needless to say, I'll give you a hand
with the music-related stuff.
予算も　そこそこ出てるしな
We do have a bit of funding, after all...
それって美術とかも　凝ったことができるってこと？
You mean we can go hardcore
with the artwork?
衣装とかも？
The costumes, too?
まあ　そこそこだけどな
Well, I did say "a bit of..."
Well, if we have to do something anyway.
まあどうせ　何かやらなきゃなんだしね
歌と踊りか
- Singing and dancing?
- I can be a stagehand, right?
裏方とかでもいいんだよね
But I've got cram school.
でも俺　塾あるしな
- And I have my part-time job.
- Hey, it's all good!
あっ　私もバイト
いいんじゃね？
I've got practice, too,
so I won’t be much help,
俺も部活あるし　あんま手伝えねえと思うけど
but if we each do as much as we can.
それぞれやれる範囲で頑張れば
Right, committee member?
なっ！？　実行委員
おっ　おう　もちろん
Of course!
Um, after hearing your feedback, of course,
あの　もちろんみんなの意見を聞いて　それぞれ分担を決めたいと思います
we'd like to allocate all the roles.
- Well, in that case...
- Yeah.
まあ　それなら
Well, not like there's anything else I want to do.
まっ　他にやりたいこと　あるわけじゃないしね
Hey, what about casting?
ねえ　配役は？　これ主役だけ　すげえ大変そうだけど
Looks like the only really
demanding role is the heroine.
あっ　それもこれから
Well, that's another thing we'll be...
えっ？　主役って成瀬じゃねえの？
Isn't Naruse going to play the heroine?
えっ！？　やらねえの！?
You’re not?
すごい
All right, then it's settled.
決まりだな
The prince appears before the girl
who 'd lost the ability to speak.
言葉を失った少女の元に　王子様が現れる
Because other encounter with the prince,
王子様と出会ったことで　少女の中に愛の言葉が　どんどん生まれてくる
words of love begin to proliferate
inside the girl's heart.
しかし少女は　それをこえにすることができない
But the girl...
is unable to voice them.
One day, an assassination attempt
is made on the prince,
そしてある時　王子様が暗殺されそうになり
玉子の策略により　犯人が少女とされてしまう
and thanks to a ruse by the Egg,
the girl is charged with the crime.
Because she can 't speak,
声が出ないため　誤解を解くことができなかった少女は
she fails to clear up the misunderstanding,
and is captured by all the people
she'd hurt till then and is sentenced to death.
今まで自分が傷つけた人々に　捕まり処刑されることになる
王子が見守るなか　処刑台の上で首をはねられる少女
As the prince looks on,
the girl 's head is chopped off on the scaffold.
That's when the words begin to gush out
of the girl's head...
すると少女の首から　言葉があふれ始める
「王子を愛してる」と
"I love the prince."
なんかグロいな
I don’t know, it's pretty gory.
But I don’t think it's bad for an ending!
でも悪くないと思うな　このラスト
You don’t?
そうか？
少女が死んでから　みんながその真意に　気づくんでしょう？
After the girl dies,
everyone realizes the truth, right?
It clears things up with the prince.
王子の誤解も解けて…
Isn't Gon, the Little Fax like that, too?
「ごんぎつね」とかってそうじゃない？　ちゃんと童話っぱいというか
It's got that fairy-tale vibe.
Well, I guess it's better than
a random happy ending.
まあテキトーなハッピーエンドよか　いいか
うん　まあ　ありなんじゃね
Yeah. I think it works.
それにしても王子が重要な役なんだよな
Still, the prince is such a crucial role.
これを俺がやるのか
And I'm the one who has to play him?
お前なんか　まだ人間だからマシだろ　俺なんて玉子だぞ　玉子！
At least you’re a human!
I'm an egg. An egg!
いや　別に　成瀬のせいじゃねえけどよ
Not that it's your fault, Naruse.
What's wrong with that?
I bet you'll look cute!
いいじゃない　かわいいよ　きっと
お前はいいよな　コーラスと罪人だっけ？
Lucky you. You’re in the chorus
and one of the criminals, right?
What choice do we have? We told them we'd do
everything we could as committee members.
仕方ないでしょ
実行委員としてできるだけ頑張るって　言っちゃったんだから
その結果　メインの役が全部　実行委員に押しつけられるとはなあ
And of course, all the main characters
were forced upon the committee members.
Girl/Jun Naruse Egg/Daiki
Tasaki Prince/Takumi Sakagami
玉子…　玉子なあ…
An egg. An egg...
いい加減　諦めなさい
Just resign yourself already.
Bu“
でもよぉ…
Naruse, you just need to write
the lyrics for the ending, right?
成瀬は　あと　最後の歌詞だけだっけ？
Do you think you'll be able to say
what you really want to say?
それで言えそうか？
本当にしゃべりたいことってのは
I see.
そっか
もう風は冷てえなあ
The wind feels cold now.
Yeah, it might be torture for us
to go on eating up here.
んー　ここで飯食うのは　もうきついかもな
失った言葉が叫び出す
The words she'd lost start to shout out...
Start to shout out
"I love you."
愛していると叫び出す
By the way, does this
have a title yet?
そういや　これ　タイトル決まってんのか？
ああ　たしか「青春の向こう脛」？
Yeah, I think it's The Shin of Youth.
That's so lame!
It has nothing to do with the story!
ダッセ！　てか　中身と全然　合ってねえぞ
はーい
Coming! Oh, my, welcome!
あらあら　いらっしゃい　拓ちゃん？
Are you here for Taku?
Yes.
はい
入って入って
Come on in!
Taku, your friend is here!
拓ちゃん　お友達よ
Excuse me!
失礼します
Oh, my, what a spirited young man!
あら　元気がいいわね
あっ　すみません
S-Sorry...
- Hey, you’re early.
- It's okay.
おう　早いな
いいのよ
If it's a 30'clock call time,
showing up at 2:50 is a no-brainer.
３時集合ったら　２時50分に集まんのが普通だろ
Hey, you can leave that open.
This place is more or less soundproof.
あっ　そこ開けといて　ここ一応　防音だから
Right. Pretty amazing.
すげえな
Well, at least in number.
まあ数だけはあるから　決まってないラストの曲の参考にでも
We can use them to decide
the last number we haven't- -
Hey, I don't know much about music,
so I'm counting on you for that.
まあ俺は音のことは　よく分かんねえから
よろしく頼むわ
Anyway, where are the others?
それより　他のやつらは？
相沢たちは　もう来ると思う
Aizawa and Iwaki should be
here any minute.
Nito and Naruse will come after
they're done shopping for the costume people.
仁藤と成瀬は衣装係に頼まれた　買い出ししてから来るってさ
By the way, I hear
you and Nito used to go out.
そういや　お前　仁藤と付き合ってたんだってな
What? HOW did- -
そっ！？　んな…　あっ　いや…
Uh, that was back when
we were in junior high.
そんなのは　その…　中学の時の話で　ちょっとだけそんな感じに…
We were briefly an item- -
Well, Nito's apparently seeing
someone else now.
ああ　仁藤　今　別に男いるらしいしな
あっ　まあそりゃ　いるんじゃねえの？　知らねえけど
Of course she has someone.
Not that I know anything about it.
- Let's play, Takumi!
- Hey, they're here.
拓実君　あーそばー！
おっ　来たな
Sorry, can you help me
move the sofa?
わりぃ　ちょっと　ソファ動かすの手伝ってくんね？
Taku, your friends are here!
拓ちゃん　お友達よ
Everybody must be there already by now.
もうみんな集まってる時間だね　ちょっと急ごうか
Shall we get a move on?
Let's see, on the map.
えっと　地図…
Naruse, have you been to
Sakagami's house before?
成瀬さん　坂上君の家　行ったことあるの？
I see.
そっか
Just once, when we were
thinking up the story.
Just once, when we were thinking up the story.
He set music to my words with the piano.
えっ！?　坂上君がピアノを？
Sakagami played the piano?
It feels so strange.
It feels so strange. Going over to a friend's
house, going shopping with a friend.
It never really seemed
possible till now...
友達…
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry! Having the nerve to call you my friend when
we're only on the Outreach committee together...!
違うの　あの…　私も　成瀬さんと友達になれて　うれしいよ
I'm glad that we
got to be friends, too!
You totally make me want to cheer you on.
ホント応援したくなる
My heart
心は叫ばない
just won 't shout it out
伝えたいことあった気がするの
I can't help but feel
that there was something
I wanted to say
...Like this?
って感じだけど
Hey, not bad.
悪くないじゃん
うん　ラストの寂しい感じと　合ってると思う
I think it matches
the melancholy of the ending.
岩木がクラシックとか言い出した時は　どうしようかと思ったけどな
When Iwaki said classical music,
I wasn't sure what we were gonna do!
いいんじゃね「悲惨」
Works in: me, 'Ms Misery.
Pathétique!
「悲愴」！
大して変わんねえだろ
Not much difference.
Oh yes, they are different!
変わるよ！
ベートーベン先生に謝れ
- Apologize to Master Beethoven!
- Okay...
んじゃまあ　とりあえずこれで　曲は全部　決まったってことかな？
Now we've got all the songs
picked out, right?
よーし　あとはアレンジだな
All right! Now for the arrangements!
We might need to tweak the lyrics, too.
歌詞の調整も要るかも
Also, the choreography and direction!
それと振り付けと演出ね
何にせよ　あと一踏ん張り
In any case, just one more push!
いやぁ　結構　時間かかったねえ
Boy, that took up a lot of time, huh?
ホント　こんだけ量があると　やっぱ迷うよなぁ
True that. Having so much material
is pretty daunting, huh?
Yeah, but this room really gets me fired up!
いやぁ　でもこの部屋　テンション上がるわ
ごめんね　手伝ってもらっちゃって
So sorry to make you help me!
あっ　そのお菓子　そこの器に出しちゃって
Oh, those sweets?
Put them in that bowl, will you?
おいしいのよ　それ
They're quite good, you know.
ねえ　さっきの曲…
Tell me, the song we just heard...
あれ弾いてたの　たっくんよね？
That was Takkun playing, wasn't it?
Is that right?
そう…　あの曲　息子も好きだったのよねえ
That song. My son loved it.
Since Takkun was such a good pianist,
たっくん　ピアノ上手だったから
昔は　よくあの部屋で　家族そろって
the whole family used to gather
in that room and listen to him play...
たっくんのピアノ　聞いてたんだけどねえ
順ちゃん？
Jun?
あら　何かしら？　えーと…
Oh, my. What is it?
Let's see...
What are you doing?
何してんの？
Oh! Takkun.
What does this say?
あら　たっくん　これ何て？
What happened to Sakagami's parents?
うちもさ　両親　離婚してんだ　母親のほうが出てったんだけど
My parents are divorced, too.
My mom who left us, and...
親父もそれから　仕事が忙しいとかって
After that, my dad's been busy
with work or whatever...
俺のことは　祖父ちゃん祖母ちゃんに預けっぱ
and left me in my grandparents' care.
まっ　年に１回　顔見りゃいいほうで
Well, I guess we see each other
once a year, at most.
あれ　拓ちゃん？
Taku?
手伝う？
Can I help?
いや　大丈夫　すぐ行くよ
No, we're good.
We'll be right there.
All right, then. Thanks for having us!
そいじゃ　お邪魔しました
See you around, Taku!
またね　拓ちゃん
See you at school!
学校で
うん　気をつけてな
Take care, all right?
なあ　本屋寄ってこうぜ
- Hey, let's stop by the book store.
駅までバスだよね
うん　いいよ
- We're taking the bus to the station, right?
じゃ　行こっか
Shall we go?
Are you sure you didn't need
to take that train? What's up?
何だ？
Are you sure you didn't
need to take that train?
The doctor told me
I still shouldn't be running,
医者から　まだ走んなって言われてっから　なるべく歩くようにしてんだが
so I'm trying to walk as much as I can.
Wait, you don’t want
to walk with me?
もしかして　一緒に歩くの　嫌だったか？
Still, that was pretty awesome, huh?
それにしても
すごかったな　相沢も岩木も　すげえ音楽　詳しくて
Both Aizawa and Iwaki
really know their music.
And Sakagami looked so cool,
playing the piano.
坂上も　ピアノ　カッコよかった
クラスの連中もよ　色んな得意なもんとかあって　成瀬も…
The people in our class
all have their talents and skills.
So do you, Naruse.
まあ　俺が今まで　何も見てなかったってことだな
Well, I guess I wasn't paying
any attention till now.
何だ？
What is it?
That's so admirable of you.
To realize that yourself.
Jeez! You talking to a kid?
ったく　ガキ相手かよ
ほら　行こうぜ
Come on, let's go.
I'm the one who never paid any attention.
私こそ何も見ていなかった
The young girl had received
such precious, blissful words...
とても尊く　幸せな言葉を　もらった少女は
しかし王子の悲しみには　気づいてはいなかったのです
But she wasn't aware of the prince 's grief.
What kind of words
could the girl utter to the prince?
少女は王子様に　どんな言葉をあげられる？
えっ！？　ラストを変えたい？
You want to change the ending?
でも成瀬…
But Naruse...
This is the new ending.
- Just before execution,
「処刑を受ける直前　少女が　全てを諦めた瞬間　王子が少女をかばう」
おーし　妖精　そろそろ合わせやるぞ
- All right, fairies! Let's try it together now!
- The prince rushes to protect her.
とりあえず歌詞見ながらやろう
- Let's look at the lyrics for now.
- At the prince's urging,
the people ended up forgiving her.
「王子の説得で人マは　少女を許してくれた」
The girl, the prince, and everyone else as well
all get a happy ending...
「少女と王子　そして　みんなそろってハッピーエンド」
I just thought that the elderly
would enjoy a happy ending more...
つまり　今のラストを変えて　もう１曲足すってこと？
ポケット　手をつっこみゃ
We don’t have much time, so cut the
sad last song, and just act out?
マッチの箱一つ
I see. I did like the lyrics
we've got now, you know.
そっか　今の歌詞も　よかったんだけどな
そんな寒かないのに
Sure, they're gloomy, but...
確かに暗いけど　あの　「愛していると叫び出す」ってとことか
The part where she shouts out, "I love you."
おまえは火をつけた
It felt that her repressed feelings
were really precious to her.
何つうか　押し込めた気持ちが
すごい大事なもんなんだろうなって　感じがして
That's what it felt like to me.
揺られる炎　浮かび…
But I agree, a happy ending
would appeal more to the masses!
まあでもハッピーエンドのほうが　確かに万人向けだろうし…
Stop! Stop!
ストップ　ストップ
What's the problem, Aizawa?
何だよ　相沢
えっ？　どっか間違えた？
Did we mess up somewhere?
No, that's not it.
いや　違くてさぁ
Then what's wrong?
じゃ　何なの？
Aizawa?
相沢？
It's just...!
なんかさ！
This song is about us evil fairies
deceiving the girl,
この曲って俺たち　邪悪な妖精が　少女をだまして
街を燃やし　人々を皆殺しって歌だろ？
burning down the town,
and massacring the people, right?
So is it really okay for us
to sing it so merrily?
それを　こんなに楽しげに　歌っていいもんかなってさ
Well, what are we supposed to do?
We're ones doing the deceiving,
so of course we're happy!
こっちは　だますほうなんだから　当たり前でしょ
Mismatched lyrics and music.
Happens all the time!
歌詞の中身と曲が　ズレてんのなんて　よくあるし
そのギャップが　面白いんじゃない？
It's that dissonance that makes it riveting,
don’t you think?
悪いな　成瀬　ちょっと思いついたことがあってさ
Sorry about this, Naruse.
Something just hit me, see.
About that last song...
その…　ラストのことなんだけど
Oh, hey, I'm all for the happy ending!
ああ　いや　ハッピーエンドは賛成なんだけどさ
元のラストの雰囲気も　よかったなあとか考えてたらさ
But when I started thinking how great
the atmosphere of the original ending was.
Let's see...
えーっと…
ハッピー…
Happy...
The song we heard the other day in class.
この前　授業で聞いたやつ
おっ　結構ハマる…か？
It actually fits pretty well, I guess.
昔　見たミュージカルでさ　全く違う２つの歌を一緒に歌うってのがあって
In this musical I saw years ago,
there was a number where they sang
two different songs at once.
And I remembered how amazing it was,
それがすごくよかったの
listening to Aizawa and the others talking.
相沢たちの話　聞いてて思い出してさ
I learned this one from my dad, too.
これもさ　親父に教えてもらったんだ
I left you hanging yesterday, didn't I?
昨日　話　中途半端だったよな
My parents were already fighting all the time
before I got into junior high...
うちの両親　俺が中学上がる前くらいから　もめること多くなってさ
My mom wanted me
to get into a private school,
私立行かせようとする母親に　その頃　ピアノに夢中だった俺が反発して
but I was so hooked on the piano
at the time, and I rebelled.
And my dad defended me.
それを親父がかばって…　みたいな
I ended up going to a public school,
結局　そのまま公立行ったんだけど　それから両親の仲は悪くなる一方で…
but the discord between
my parents only got worse.
And what happened next
was what I told you yesterday.
そこからは昨日　言ったとおり
Even though my own selfishness
was the cause,
俺のわがままが　きっかけだったのに
I couldn’t do anything.
I couldn’t say a word.
何もできなくて　何も言えなくて
俺のせいって思ったら　ピアノ触んのも怖くなった
Since I blamed myself,
I got scared to even touch the piano.
There's no way that it was your fault!
Then the same goes for
what happened to your family.
だったら成瀬の家のことだって　俺はお前のせいだなんて思えないよ
I can't believe that it was your fault.
That's probably just how it is.
きっと　そんなもんなんだよな
That's not true that something or somebody
being 100% to blame or wrong.
何かが　誰かが100パー悪いとか　ダメとか　そういうのってきっとない
Anyway, what I wanted
to suggest was,
んで　何が言いたいかって言うとさ
if both of these endings are
what you really want to say,
どっちのラストも成瀬の　「本当にしゃべりたいこと」なんだったら
why don’t we somehow
convey both of them?
どうせなら　その２つともを　伝えられるようにできたらなって
Just a thought I had.
思ったんだけど
Sakagami, you’re amazing.
いや…　成瀬？
No...
Sakagami, you’re amazing.
You’re amazing.
Would you mind playing it again?
Would you mind playing it again? I want to listen well
and will put everything I want to convey in that song.
I want to cram it all in.
My older self as 100 is talking to me
Multiply the tiny things which I like doing
私の王子様…
It will
Make sky bluer and bluer
Prince
More than ever before
Music Room
It will make me smile a little more
My older self as 100 is talking to me
Community Outreach Event
Arts/Sports-related
link together the notes I love
It'll become a harmony
The Shin of Youth Girl/Jun Naruse
Egg/Daiki Tasaki Prince/Takumi Sakagami
The sounds are sweeter and sweeter
Please come see this, if you want.
Echoing nicely around me
おはよう
Morning!
本番もう明日だよ　まだ歌詞とか不安なのに
We're going on for real tomorrow!
And I'm still not sure about the lyrics...
私だって　てか振りも　まだ不安なとこあるし
Same here. I'm still worried
about the choreography.
I know, right?
だよね
おっ　はよー　坂上
Morning, Sakagami!
Morning.
はよ　早いな
You’re here early.
まあね
Sure am!
あっ　仁藤
Hey, Nito. About getting permission
to use the gym this after- -
昼の体育館の使用許可…
Oh, right!
あっ　そうだった　ごめん　すぐ行ってくる
Sorry! I'll take care of it right away!
あっ　菜月　ちょっと待ってよ
Hey! Natsuki?
えっ？　いや　俺も…
- No. I was going to join you.
- Wait up, will you?
The sky is bluer and bluer
More than ever before
It will make me smile a little more
What will I talk to younger self
If I were 100 years old.
0K!
オッケー
We're done with rehearsals for all parts!
リハーサル　全パート終了
よっしゃーっ
やった
All right, it's getting late,
so clear up and get out of here!
よーし　じゃ　もういい時間だし　とっとと片付けて帰れよ
What?
Don't "what?" me.
「えー」じゃない
Tomorrow, the first years
will be using the stage first,
明日は１年が先にステージ使うんだから　しっかり片付けんだぞ
so make sure you do a good job clearing up!
んじゃ　やろうか
Okay, let's get to it.
だな
じゃ　先に大きいもんから
Then let's start with the big stuff...
おーい
Hey!
力仕事要員　連れてきたぞ
I brought in the troops for the heavy lifting!
- Ikkun!
いっくん！
- It's the baseball team!
野球部じゃん
All right!
やった
あいつら…
Those guys.
Where should we take this?
- That's fragile, so be careful, okay?
- Hey, could you give us a hand?
っと…　おっ？
All right. Hey.
I'll take that.
もらいます
Hey, thanks.
おう　悪いな
全然ス　てか　いいんスか　それ
Not at all.
But is your elbow okay?
ん？ああ　やっと医者から許可が出てな　来週からは練習にも出ていいってよ
The doctor finally cleared me.
I could start practicing next week.
もうちょっとだけ待っててくれや
Wait for me just a little longer.
Right.
ウス
Hey, Natsuki?
あっ　菜月　教室　戻るんなら　これもお願い
If you're heading back to the classroom,
could you take this, too?
えっ？　あっ　ちょっと待って　えっと…
Oh, hold up a second.
Then can you go, too, Sakagami?
んじゃ　坂上も行ってくれる？
なあ　仁藤
Hey, Nito.
なあ　なんか最近　変じゃないか？
Aren't you acting
a little weird lately?
何が？
Like how?
何がって　その…
Like how? You know...
別に何も！　ウッ！?
It's nothing, all right?
えっ？　何？
What is it?
Really, Ikkun, you’re such a bad boy!
もう　いっくんてば悪い子じゃん
Well, what can I do?
しょうがないだろ？
Lately we've been so busy prepping for this,
we could never be alone.
ここんとこ準備とかで　全然　二人きりになれなかったし
もう　だからって　こんなとこでぇ…
But in a place like this...
でも…
もう　何なの　あれ？　この忙しい時に
How could they
when it's crunch time for us?
いくら付き合ってるからって　がっ　学校であんなことするなんて…
I don’t care if they're dating.
Doing that stuff at school.
Dating.
付き合ってる…
あっ　いや　仁藤も付き合ってるやつ　いるんだよな
Well... You’re dating
someone now, right?
How'd you know?
なんで？
I heard about it the other day from Tasaki.
その…　ちょっと前に田崎から…
Nito?
仁藤？
Nito!
仁藤
来ないで！
Stay away from me!
Wait, you...
でも　お前…
You’re crying.
泣いて…
なあ　仁藤
Look, Nito...
いいから！
Forget it!
もういいから　あとは私　やっとく
Just forget it.
I'll take care of the rest.
Put that down, and...
それ置いて　早く成瀬さんとこ　行ってあげて
Go be with Naruse!
えっ？　なんでそこで成瀬の名前が　出てくんの
Why would you bring her up now?
だって好きなんでしょ　成瀬さんのこと
Because you’re in love, aren't you?
With Naruse?
ちょっ　ちょっと待て　何だ　そりゃ
Hold up! Where'd you get that idea?
俺は別に成瀬のこと　好きとか　そんなんじゃない
It's not like I'm in love with Naruse!
え…　だって成瀬さんのこと　気にかけてるじゃない　すっごく！
But, you’re always concerned about her!
I mean really!
ああ　かけてるよ
That's right, I am concerned!
でも　それは…
But that's because... I don’t know.
何て言うか…　前にも言ったろ
Didn't I tell you before?
Naruse's been trying so hard.
So I want to cheer her on!
成瀬　すげえ頑張ってっから　応援したいって
それが好きってことなんじゃないの？
Isn't that what being in love is?
I'm telling you, you’re wrong!
だから違うって！
何　人の気持ち　勝手に決めつけてんだよ
Why are you making assumptions
about other people's feelings?
I can't tell!
そんなの分かんないよ　坂上君の気持ち　全然！
I can't tell what you’re feeling at all!
Yeah... guess not.
そうだよな
分かんないんだ　思ってることは　ちゃんと口にしなきゃ
You can't tell what I'm thinking.
I've got to put them into words.
俺…
I always regretted it.
後悔してた　あん時
That day, when you tried
to reach out to me...
仁藤が　手を伸ばしてくれようとしたこと
I knew you were,
but I didn't do anything about it.
分かってたのに　自分からは何もしなかったこと
だから成瀬が頑張ってんの見て　俺…
That's why...
Seeing Naruse trying so hard...
I... I thought, "This time I'll- -
俺も「今度は」って…
私はね　あのあと　私たちの関係　うやむやになって…
As for me, after that,
things between us got so vague...
But I was glad it ended up that way.
でも　それでよかったって思ってた
If I asked you. If I said it out loud,
聞いたら　口に出しちゃったら　本当に終わっちゃうって　ずっと…
I thought it would really be over
between us. All this time...
Does that mean...
それって…
Then the guy you’re seeing...
じゃ付き合ってるやつって…
But that's not how I should've handled it.
でも　それじゃいけなかったんだよ
And now that I know that I handled it wrong,
いけなかったって　分かっちゃったから　だから私「応援する」って
That's why I said I'd cheer you on.
仁藤　俺は…
Nito, I- -
そろそろ行こ　みんな待ってるよ
We should get going.
Everyone's waiting.
Nito...
仁藤…
ごめん　今は　もう聞きたくない
Sorry. I don’t want to hear it now.
でも…
But...
ピアノ　また聞けてうれしかった
It made me happy
to hear you play the piano again.
あれ？
What's wrong?
どした？
These are the bags
I asked Naruse to bring.
成瀬さんに頼んでた　かばん　こんなとこにあった
はっ？　成瀬は？
Where's Naruse?
なんか急用みたい？
Seems like it's something urgent?
いっ　痛い…
Ow...
いっ　痛い！　痛い
It hurts... it hurts... it hurts!
痛い…
It's not your stomach, I see.
おなかじゃないね
It's your heart that hurts.
痛いのは胸だ
It's the pain of youth.
青春の痛みだ
Inflicted on you for breaking the seal...
封印を破った君への
I haven't spoken! Hardly at all!
しゃべってない！　ほとんど
When you’re told not to speak,
しゃべるなというのはね　言葉だけじゃないんだよ
it's not just about words.
君は心が　おしゃべりすぎるんだ
You have a heart that talks too much.
Takumi Sakagami...
坂上拓実が好きだ　好きだ　好きだ　好きだ　好きだ　好きだ　好き…
I love him I love him I love him I love him
I love him I love him I love him...
Stop it!
やめて！
So you see?
だから　ほら！
Your egg is full of cracks now.
君の玉子は　もうヒビだらけ
Aha, here it comes.
あー　出てくるよ
ド口ド口した白身　孵化しかけの黄身
The slimy egg whites.
The about-to-be-hatched yolk...
I'm very disappointed in you.
君にはガッカリしたよ
Let's bring this superficial
imprisonment to an end.
もう中途半端に閉じ込めるのは　終わりにしよう
All right, It's time for...
さあ　いよいよ…
Some scrambled eggs.
スクランブルエッグだ
Community Outreach Event
To think it would snow at this time of year!
こんな時期に雪なんてね
Community Outreach Event
いや　焦ったよ
いや　寒いね
Community Outreach Event
ねえ　まだ見つかんないの？　成瀬さん
Hey!
Has anyone found Naruse yet?
No. And we haven't heard
from anyone else, either.
ダメ　他からも連絡来ない
There's nowhere else to look
on the school grounds!
学校ん中　もう捜すとこないよ
Not hearing back from the guys
patrolling outside, either.
外　回ってる連中からも　連絡来ねえ
Is she really at school?
ホントに学校にいんのか？
Well, her shoes were in her locker!
でも口ッカーに靴　あったし
Sakagami, what about her cell phone?
坂上　ケータイは？
No good. I can't get through.
ダメだ　つながんない　留守電も　もう…
And her voicemail's--
Sorry. I can't play the heroine. I
was carried away. Really sorry.
なんで…
ヒロインできねえって
She can't play the heroine?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Why so suddenly?
何だ　そりゃ
なんで急にそんな！?
It's no good. I can't call her.
ダメだ　やっぱこっちからは…
What are we gonna do?
どうすんだよ
ヒロインいなくちゃ　始まんないよ
Without our heroine, we've got nothing!
成瀬さん　昨日　急用とか言ってたの　何か関係あんのかな
You think this has something to do with
Naruse's urgent business yesterday?
あっ　そうだ！
Hey! When you two went back
to the classroom yesterday,
お前ら昨日　教室行った時　成瀬に会わなかったか？
did you run into Naruse?
えっ？　昨日って？
Yesterday...
You took stuff back
to the classroom, right?
教室に荷物　持ってったろ？
そん時　成瀬も　かばん　取りに行ってたから
It was around that time when
Naruse went to pick up some bags.
えっ！？　あの時って
Around that time?
Then that sound we heard...
じゃ　あの物音って…
Naruse heard what we were saying.
成瀬さんに聞かれた？
Heard you? Heard you say what? Hey!
聞かれた？　何をだよ　おい！
Well...
それは…
Is Naruse here?
成瀬　来た？
We looked for her off the school gro- -
学校の外も…
何やってんだよ　お前らは　こんな大事な時によぉ
What were you thinking?
At a crucial time like this!
Hey, Dai...
おい　大ちゃん
けっ　けど…　それが原因かなんて
But we don’t know if that's
the reason, unless Naruse...
その…　成瀬が俺のことを…　とか…
お前が！
You!
You can't be...
お前がそれを…
What am I gonna do?
どうしよう　私…
Natsuki...
菜月
えっ　何？　つまり…
What, you mean...
That thing you call
the tangles of blind love?
チジョーのもつれってやつ？
何だ　それ
- What's up with that?
- Is that why Naruse's a no-show?
成瀬　来ない理由って　それなの？
What's that?
何それ？
Isn't that kind of outrageous?
ちょっと　あり得なくない？
After we all worked so hard to get ready.
みんなで頑張って　準備したのに
ちょっと最低だよね　成瀬さん
That's kind of a jerk move
by Naruse, don't you think?
Hey!
おい
お前は　どうすんだ
What are you gonna do?
I...
俺は…
おーい　やっぱ成瀬の家　誰も出ない…
Hm, nobody’s picking up
at Naruse's house either.
What is it?
何？
いや　なんか…
Well, it's just that...
みんな
You guys, I'm Sorry!
ごめん！
別に拓が謝ることじゃ…
No need for you to apologize, Taku...
The idea was ours, and with
your cooperation, we made it this far.
俺たちが言い出して
みんなに協力してもらって　ここまでやってきたのに
成瀬は　それを全部ぶち壊そうとしてる
And yet, Naruse is about to destroy it all.
And I think that's a truly heinous betrayal.
それは本当にひどい裏切りだと思う
でも俺　それでもあんなに必死に…
But I...
Even so...
She was so frantic. Even though
her stomach hurts her when she talks,
しゃべると腹痛くなんのに
無理してでも頑張ってた　あいつを見てたから
she ignored it so she could push on.
だからやっぱり
And since I saw that...
どうしても　あいつに　舞台に立ってほしいんだ
I want her to get up
on that stage, no matter what!
そりゃさ　うちらだって　成瀬　頑張ってたの知ってるけど
Well, sure. We know how hard
Naruse was working, too.
でも実際　来ないんだからさぁ
But the fact is, she's a no-show.
うん　だから俺に捜しに行かせてほしい
So I want you to let me go look for her.
ちょっと何言ってんの？
What are you saying?
坂上までいなくなって　どうすんだよ
What are we supposed to do
if you leave, too?
岩木　曲は全部　お前が作ってんだから　歌も全部　歌えんだろ
Iwaki, it was you who wrote all the songs,
so you can sing them all, right?
えっ！？　まあ…
Well...
じゃ　坂上　戻ってくるまで　王子　頼む
Then until Sakagami gets back,
I want you to play the prince.
仁藤
Nito?
お前　成瀬に振り付けたんだから　曲も覚えてんだろ？
Since you’re the one who directed Naruse,
you know the songs, don’t you?
成瀬の代わり　頼むわ
I want you to take Naruse's place.
わっ　私！?
Me?
もともと１回しか出番ねえし　何とかなるだろ
You were only going on once anyway,
so you can take this.
And Iwaki, the fairy and the prince
don’t come on at the same time, either!
岩木も妖精と王子は　かぶらねえし
まっ　まあ…
Well, no...
Tasaki..."
田崎…
俺からも頼む　どうか少しだけ　成瀬にチャンスをくれ
Let me ask for your cooperation, too!
I just want you to give Naruse
the slightest chance.
このとおり！
Please!
わっ　私も精一杯やるから
I promise to do my very best, too!
私も菜月の分　倍踊るよ
And I'll dance enough
for both Natsuki and me!
陽子　フォーメーション変わるとこ　確認しよ
Yoko, let's go over the part
where the formation changes again.
Iwaki, if you’re not up to it,
I wouldn’t mind playing the prince.
岩木　自信ないなら　俺が王子やってもいいぞ
相沢じゃ　衣装　入んないだろ
You wouldn’t fit into the costume, Aizawa!
Hey.
おい
頼むぞ
I'm counting on you.
待ってろ　成瀬
Wait for me, Naruse!
Why, hello. Ms. Naruse!
あら　成瀬さん
The first years just finished
their performance now.
ちょうど今　１年生が終わったところですよ
よかったら隣　空いてますよ
If you like, this seat next to us is open!
ああ　坂上？
Hey, Sakagami?
ごめん　成瀬は　まだ…
Sorry. Still no sign of Naruse.
あっ　じゃなくて　先　行った田崎から伝言
Oh, it's not that. Here's a message
from Tasaki, who went an ahead.
なんか客席に　成瀬のお母さん　来てたって
He says that Naruse's mam
is in the audience.
うん　分かった　ありがとう
Gotcha. Thanks!
We'll head over as soon as I find her.
見つけたらすぐ行くから　うん…
クソッ…
Dammit. What are you doing, Naruse?
何やってんだよ　成瀬
The me who never speaks was born.
あっ　そういや　あん時　成瀬が言ってた
Come to think of it.
Naruse did mention that day...
It all started with...
全ての事の始まりは…
The ball at the castle!
城の舞踏会…
They're taking a long time, huh?
なんか遅いね
- At the glittering golden castle...
きんぴかのお城で　夜ごとくりかえす
ねえ　緊張してきた
- Night after night, it happens.
なんか腹　いてえ
俺も…
- Me, too.
紳士と淑女つどう…
- Attended by gentlemen and ladies...
おい　進行の先生から連絡だぞ
- That ball...
あの～
スタートは　もう延ばせないって
- He can't delay our start time any longer.
- That ball...
ちょっと仁藤？
あの舞踏会
- Hey, Nito?
- That ball....
- That ball...
なっ　何？
What?
What's this? You always dance
in a short skirt as a cheerleader.
何だよ　部活じゃ短いスカート　ヒラヒラさせて踊ってんのに
Have you lost your nerve?
怖じ気づいてんのか？
Maybe.
そうかも…　怖じ気づいてた　きっと　ずっと…
I'd lost my nerve, probably.
All this time...
私　はっきりするの逃げてた
I might have been running away
from making things clear.
But I'm done with that!
でも　もうやめる　そういうの
All right, then let's go!
おっし　じゃ　行くか
おう！
Right!
緊張してきちゃう
Once upon a time, in a certain land...
昔々　ある所にお城の舞踏会に　憧れる貧しい少女がおりました
There lived a poor young girl
who yearned to go to the ball at the castle.
きんぴかのお城で
At the glittering golden castle
Night after night, it happens
夜ごとくりかえす
Attended by gentlemen and ladies
紳士と淑女つどう
あの舞踏会
あれ？　主役って　別の人じゃなかったっけ？
- That ball...
- Her fluttering dress is like a red fish
翻るドレスは赤い魚みたい
やっぱり…　ダメなんじゃない
ホールを泳いでく　尾びれゆらして
- She swims through the hall, waving her tail...
声出てんじゃん　菜月！
ちょっと硬い感じするけどね
「君　ここで何をしているんだい？」
- What are you doing here, may I ask?
うわあ　私も緊張してきた
頼むぞ　坂上！
- I'm counting an you, Sakagami!
とっとと成瀬　連れてこい
Bring Naruse back as soon as you can!
くらい　ならちょっとくらい　夢をみるくらい
If it's dark, then just a little bit
- Let me dream
こっちか？
もうこんな時間…
- But if I find Naruse...
でも　もし成瀬　見つかって　そしたら　俺…
くらい　まやかしだって　いいから踊ってみたい
- Even if it's a dark deception
I don 't care, I want to dance
Naruse.
成瀬…
行こう　成瀬
Let's go, Naruse.
Everybody's waiting.
みんなが待ってる
I can't go back anymore.
もう…　戻れない
Naruse? You- -
成瀬　お前…
It's already started, hasn't it?
もう始まっちゃったんでしょ
No, there's still time!
いや　まだ大丈夫だ　今　みんなが何とかやってくれてるから
Because they're somehow getting by for now.
無理だよ
It's hopeless.
I can't sing anymore.
もう歌えない
Because my prince doesn't exist anymore.
私の王子様は　もういないから
- Naruse- -
- Don’t come near me!
成瀬
来ないでっ！
Don’t make me shout!
叫ばせないで　また　おなか痛くなっちゃうじゃない
My stomach will start hurting again,
don’t you see?
ああっ　歌ならいいとか　ダメだったんだ
Thought I could do it if I sang...
But it didn't work out!
Talking.
しゃべったり　心がしゃべったり　やっぱりダメだった！
My heart talking.
It didn't work, after all!
It was just like the Egg said!
玉子の言うとおりだった　しゃべったりするから不幸になった！
Because I spoke up, I became unhappy!
There was never any egg, and you know it!
玉子なんて最初からいないだろ
Yes, there is!
いるもん
There isn't!
いない
There is!
いる！
Isn't!
いない！
いないと
I need him to exist, or I'd be lost!
困るの！
舞台もメチャクチャにして…　家のこともメチャクチャにして…
I've ruined the play.
I've ruined my family.
If my being a chatterbox wasn't to blame...
私のおしゃべりのせいじゃなかったら
何の！
What am I supposed to blame it all on?
何のせいにすればいいの！
What am I supposed to do?
どうすればいいのよ
ほーう　君は罪を　犯したいと言うのかーい？
So you’re telling me
that you wish to commit a crime?
That's right! I want to dance!
そうよ　私は踊りたいの
Even knowing that it's a ball for criminals
being held at that castle.
たとえあのお城で行われているのが　罪人の舞踏会だと知っても　それでも！
Even so!
The girl makes a desperate appeal.
少女は必死に訴えます
だーったら　あいつらに負けない罪を　犯さないとなぁ
Well, in that case, you've got to
commit a crime just as grave as theirs!
そう　例えば…
That's right! For example...
Stick my hand in my packet
ポケット手をつっこみゃ
マッチの箱一つ
I've gut one box of matches
そんな寒かないのに
- It's not even that cold and you light a fire
何　あの「ボッ」ってアドリブ？
気合い入りすぎっていうか…
おまえは火をつけた
おい　大丈夫なのか？
コラ　動くな
あんた出番　次でしょ
- Aizawa is doing his best in his own way.
- The wavering flames flicker upward
相沢なりに頑張ってんでしょ
ゆれる炎　浮かびあがる
- The wavering flames flicker upward
でもよ
成瀬　心配なのは分かるけどさ
みんなだって　不安のなか頑張ってんだよ
- but we're all doing our best
even with all our misgivings.
遠く甘い生活
- A faraway, sweet life
まっ　私は来ても来なくても　どっちでもいいけど
ダンスお喋りドレスのフリル
- Dancing, talking, the frills on your dress
どっちでもやること一緒ってこと
最悪なのは舞台　失敗することでしょ
- The worst outcome would be
to mess up this musical, right?
明け方の恋遊び
- Romantic games at daybreak
もしそうなったらたぶん　成瀬が一番　後悔すると思う
- And if that were to happen,
I think Naruse would regret it the most.
燃えあがれよ焼きつくせよ
- Rise up in flames, burn it to the ground
だからどっちにしろ　成功しなきゃダメなんだよ
本音は？
あんなに練習したの　無駄にしたくねえし
True!
確かに！
Well, I guess you’re right!
まあ　そうだよな
It's too late anyway, it's already started!
何を今さら　もう始まってんだよ
ホントホント
True! True!
I wish it would just burn up!
もう全部　燃えちゃえばいい
Me.
私も　私の心も　私のおしゃべりも！
My soul.
All my chattering, too!
- Naru- -
- I've got to blame it on my talkativeness.
成瀬…
おしゃべりのせいにしなきゃ　どうしていいのか分からない
Or I wouldn’t know what to do!
I really don’t know what to do!
どうすればいいか　分かんないんだもん！
Jun Naruse!
成瀬順!
なっ…　何だよ
W-What is it?
You have a sweet voice, you know.
お前　かわいい声してるよな
Talk to me some more.
もっと　しゃべってくれよ
Say what you really want to say.
お前の本当の言葉ってやつ
Give me more of those words.
もっと俺にくれよ
はっ　話を聞いてなかったの？　ダメに決まってるでしょ
Didn't you hear what I just said?
Of course that's not gonna happen!
言葉は誰かを傷つけるもん
Words...
Words hurt other people!
俺を傷つけていいよ
You can hurt me.
傷ついていいから　お前の本当の言葉　もっと聞きたいんだ
I don’t mind if I get hurt.
I want to hear you
speak the truth some more.
成瀬！
Naruse!
じゃ　今から傷つけるから
Okay, then, I'm gonna start hurting you now.
優しいフリしてヒキョウモノ！
You pretend to be kind,
but you’re such a hypocrite!
お前なんて　時々　ワキ臭いくせに！
Your armpits smell sometimes!
You’re not even that good-looking!
顔だって　そんなによくない
ピアノがちょっと弾けるからって　モテるとか勘違いすんな　ウソつき者！
Just because you can play the piano,
don't be deluded that you're popular!
You liar!
思わせぶりなことばっか言って　いいカッコしい野郎！
You’re always leading people on.
You pretentious bastard!
Also!
それから！
That girl! That girl is equally to blame!
あの女！
あの女も同罪だ
She's a liar! And she's a goody-two-shoes!
ウソつき　いい人ぶりっこだ！ああいうのが一番　タチが悪いっ！
That's the most vile kind of person there is!
Also...
それから！
それから…
Also...
それから？
Also?
もう何も言うことなくなった
I've run out of things to say.
ホントか？
Ream?
なくなった！
I've run out!
それで全部か？　お前の本当の言葉
Is that all? All your words of truth?
名前っ！
Name!
Just now, you said my name.
さっき私の名前言った
I've never said your name before.
私　あなたの名前　言ったことない
Say it.
言ってくれ
Takumi Sakagami.
坂上…　拓実
坂上拓実
Takumi Sakagami.
Takumi Sakagami!
坂上拓実！
あれ　なんでだろ？
What? I wonder why?
俺　成瀬と同じだったよ　しゃべりはするけど
I was just like you, Naruse.
I'd talk, but...
本音とか　思ったことを言わない癖が　いつの間にかついててさ
I fell into the habit of not saying
what I really felt, somewhere along the way.
そしたら誰かに　本当に伝えたいことなんて
And then, I started believing
that there wasn't anything...
that I really wanted to tell anyone.
何にもないんじゃないかって　思うようになった
でも成瀬と会って
But then I met you.
お前は普段しゃべらないけど　ホントは伝えたいこととか　いっぱいあって…
You don’t usually talk,
but you do have so many things
you want to convey.
And I started to realize that
maybe there were many things
そしたらさ　俺も何かまだ　誰かに伝えたいこと
I wanted to tell someone
and I wanted to talk about.
しゃべりたいこと　いっぱいあったんじゃないかって…
I'm glad that I met you!
俺　お前と会えてうれしいんだ
Thanks to you, I think
I realized all kinds of things!
お前のおかげで俺　色々　気づけた気がするんだ
全部…
This is all...
Thanks to me?
私のおかげ？「せい」じゃなくて？
Not my fault?
That's right!
そうだよ　だからやっぱり　玉子なんていない！
So there isn't any egg after all!
だって　そいつの言ったことは　ウソつぱちだった
Because whatever he told you
was a pack of lies!
だって俺　お前の言葉で　うれしくなったから！
Because your words made me happy!
だから…
So- -
私も坂上君のおかげ
Me, too. It's all thanks to you, Sakagami.
It's thanks to you, to Nito,
to Tasaki, to everyone!
坂上君の　仁藤さんの　田崎君の　みんなのおかげ
だったのに…
But I...
行こう
Let's go.
みんな待ってるよ　お前のこと　待ってる
They're all waiting.
For you.
They're waiting!
I have one more thing that I want to say.
私　言いたいこと　もう１つあった
I love you, Sakagami!
私　坂上君が好き
Thanks.
ありがとう　でも俺　好きなやつがいるんだ
But I'm in love with someone else.
I knew that.
知ってたよ
The girl begins spouting
every abusive word she can think of.
少女は考えつくだけの　悪口を言いまくり…
- Let's stay and watch a little longer.
- Hurting others. Earning their dislike.
もう少し　観ていきましょう
人を傷つけ　人に嫌われ　そして気がつくと
- Hurting others. Earning their dislike.
そうよ　順ちゃんも　うちのたっくんも　すごく頑張って準備してたんだから
- Right. Jun and Takkun
worked so hard to prepare for this.
言葉を失ってしまいました
So you've lost the ability to speak!
言葉を失ったか！
That's your punishment for your crimes!
それがお前の罪への罰！
That's what everyone wants,
for you to lose your voice!
みんなが　お前の声が出ないのを望んでいるんだ
違う…
No. I never wanted that.
私　そんなこと望んでなんか…
Farewell, my voice...
私の声　さようなら　あの山のさきの
Beyond that mountain,
into the lake sleeping so deeply
ふかくねむる湖に　行ってしまった
Now it is gone
- Look, Tasaki!
ねえ　ちょっと田崎　これ　あんたの光ってる
ひとのこころ傷つける　悲しい言葉を
- The sorrowful words that scar people 's hearts
ほら　坂上からだよ
貸せっ！
えっ！？　成瀬　見つかったの？
坂上か？　見つかった！？
でも　どうすんの？　これから
拓　成瀬とこっち向かってるって
口にしたくないと泣き　行ってしまった
- Nat wanting to utter them, it subbed...
今から仁藤と入れ替え？
マジ？　拓ちゃん来んの？
でも　もう中盤過ぎてるぞ
あと出れるのって…
- But this is perfect.
- Now it' is gone
ちょうどいいじゃん
- Now it is gone
いいって何が…
このあと　「少女の心の歌声」ってあるだろ？
- Where we leave the girl who can't talk onstage,
舞台の上に　しゃべれなくなった少女　残して
おはよう　こんにちは　ごきげんはいかが
- Good morning, hello, how are you today?
裏から仁藤たちが　歌う予定だったやつ
あれ　歌いながら　出てくりゃいいじゃん
えっ？　心の声が出てくる！?
ちょっ？　それって　少女２人になっちゃうじゃん
ありふれたやりとりが　いまは恋しい
いいんだよ
- It's all good.
- Those ordinary conversations
だってミュージカルには…
- After all, musicals and miracles
go hand in hand, right?
奇跡がつきもんだろ？
- Haw I miss them now
My voice disappeared, much to everyone’s jay
わたしの声　消えたこと　みんな喜んだ
みんなわたしの言葉を　嫌ってるから
Because everyone hates the wards that I say
Heaving with sobs, my voice left me and is gone
のこされたわたしは　もう　泣くことできず
Left behind, I can no longer even cry
And so, the girl who'd lost her voice
finally collapsed under the weight of her crimes.
こうして言葉を　なくした少女は
その罰の重さに　ついに倒れてしまいました
- The girl is in despair.
But just then, a prince passes by.
絶望の少女　しかし　そこに一人の王子さまが通りががります
成瀬！
You were great, Naruse!
よかったよ　成瀬
玉子にささげよう
うん　登場も派手で面白かった
Yeah, your entrance was so dramatic.
- It was really cool!
- That was a little nerve-wracking.
でも本当によかった
ハラハラしたけどね
We were worried.
心配したんだよ
成瀬！
Naruse! Get your makeup on...
早くメイク…
beautiful words 言葉をささげよう
って
Hey, no crying!
I won’t be able to get you made up!
ちょっと泣いちゃダメ！
メイクできなくなるでしょ
Naruse, you’re on again right after this.
成瀬
すぐまた出番だからな　最後まで頼むぞ
We're counting on you till the end!
I...
私…
- I caused you all so much trouble.
みんなに…迷惑かけて…
しゃべって…
なのに…
And Still...
ほら　だから泣いちゃダメだって
Come on, we told you not to cry!
You’re seeing this through, aren't you?
最後までやるんでしょ
- Inside the egg are...
玉子の中には
てか　おなか大丈夫なの？
Egg whites gone cold and an ominous yolk
しらけた白身と　ぶきみな黄身
ああ　本当に玉子なんて　いなかったんだ
So there never really was an egg.
I'm the one who cast that curse.
呪いをかけたのは私　玉子は私
I was the egg.
Locked away inside the egg, alone. Me, myself.
１人で玉子に閉じこもってた　私自身
Just then, the world burst
into song towards the girl.
その時　世界が少女に向かって　歌い出したのです
This is it, huh? Go on!
これで最後だな　行ってこい
Now, then...
さて…
- I will call out your name
- My heart begins to shout
心が叫びだす
あなたの名前呼ぶよ
あなたのとなりで見る世界は
- I will call out your gentle name
- The world I see standing next to you
優しいあなたの名前呼ぶよ
すべてが美しい
あなたに教えられた
- You taught me to see
- Everything is so beautiful
悲しい過去も涙のあとも
とても美しいこの世界
- This beautiful world
- My sad past as well as the traces of my tears
- I will embrace this world
- I'm going to shout out
わたしは叫ぶから
この世界を抱きしめるよ
- I will embrace the whole everything
- The feelings that were born since I met you
あなたに出会い生まれた気持ち
全部まるごと抱きしめるよ
すべてを愛してる
あなたを愛している
- I love you
- I love everything about it
あなたがくれたこの世界を
あなたをこんなに愛してる
- I love you so much
- This world that you gave me
Community Outreach Event
So listen,
あのよ
俺ちょっと　成瀬に告白してくるわ
I'm gonna go confess my feelings to Naruse.
I'm starting practice again
after the weekend, you know?
俺　週明けたら練習　始めるしよ
そしたら　あんま暇ねえし
So I won’t have much spare time...
それで今から？
That's why you’re doing it now?
おう　だもんで　ちょっと抜けていいか？
So, can I step away for a second?
まだ片付け残ってっから　ちゃんと戻ってこいよ
We still have some cleaning up to do,
so make sure you come back.
おう
じゃ　ちょっと行ってくるわ
Okay, I'm going now!
なんかすごいね　田崎君
Pretty amazing, huh? That Tasaki.
仁藤…
Nito?
あのさ　この前　聞きたくないって　言ってた話の続き　してもいいか？
Listen...
The rest of that conversation
you said you didn't want to hear.
Can I talk now?
No.
やだ
Right now, it's like you’re
piggybacking onto Tasaki, so no.
今は　なんか田崎君に　便乗してるみたいで　やだ
あ…　いや　そういうわけじゃ…
No, that's not- -
Another time!
今度！
Tell me properly.
ちゃんと聞かせて
And I'll give you a proper answer.
私も…　ちゃんと答えるから
Come on! Let's get back to work!
ほら　早く戻ろ！
玉子の中には何がある？
What's inside the egg ?
All kinds of feelings locked inside.
色んな気持ちを閉じ込めて
閉じ込めきれなくなって
Then, unable to keep them locked in...
It explodes...
爆発して
And the world that's created then...
そして生まれた　その世界は…
思ったより綺麗なんだ
It is more beautiful than I ever thought.
一人でいるのが　一番楽だった
誰かと一緒にいると　僕は僕じゃない
小さい頃から　ブランコが好きで
シーソーに乗っている時は　ただ相手に合わせた
気づけば君はいつのまにか　僕のすぐ近くにいるのに
僕は僕らしく　そう普通でいられるのはなぜだろう？
それが恋と知ってしまったなら
こんな自然に話せなくなるよ
だから僕たちは似た者同士
気の合う友達だと思ってる
目の前にはいつもヒントがあり
紛れもない過去の答えがある
あきらめるなら一人でいいけど
夢を見るなら君と一緒がいい
話したい誰かがいるってしあわせだ
林檎を剥く時　母親の指先が
滑って切ってしまいそうで　嫌いと嘘ついた
何も欲しいと言わなければ　永遠に傷つかずに済む
かさぶた
僕は何回か　その瘡蓋を見て学んだ
望まない
これが恋と知ってしまったんだ
一本のコーラ　２人飲んでから
急に僕たちはドキドキとして
お互いに異性だと思い出す
今までならきっと逃げてただろう
君のことを失うのが怖い
片想いなら黙っていればいい
両思いなら気づかなければいい
話したい誰かがいるっていいもんだ
僕の部屋　片隅で漫画読んでる
君とだったら　シーソー乗ってみよう
それが恋と知ってしまったなら
こんな自然に話せなくなるよ
だから僕たちは似た者同士
気の合う友達だと思ってる
目の前にはいつもヒントがあり
紛れもない過去の答えがある
あきらめるなら一人でいいけど
夢を見るなら君と一緒がいい
話したい誰かがいるってしあわせだ
台本整理
小病
AB
翻译
走路鲨
冰蝶
校对
はばやし
总监
zwx
时间轴
阿水
压制
中津静流
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组